<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fire and Cooking on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/fire-and-cooking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fire and Cooking on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:41:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/fire-and-cooking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Foil Parcels</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/foil-parcels/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/foil-parcels/</guid>
      <description>If you have good chopping skills or want to develop them, then this activity is for you. The aim of making foil parcels is to prepare, create, and cook apples over an open fire. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and develop a foundation of wild culinary skills.
Resources Foil/Bowl/Knife/Chopping Board Zip Lock Bags Cooking Oil/Salt and Pepper/Veg Stock Cube/Range of Vegetables or Fruit Herbs (Optional) Table Spoon (tbsp) Fire Kit /Water/Gloves/Bucket Explanation Place one square of foil on top of another one and brush the top one with oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Apples</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/baked-apples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/baked-apples/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Baked apples&amp;rsquo; is a juicy outdoor activity suitable for any age. The aim of making baked apples is to prepare, create, and cook apples over an open fire. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and develop a foundation of wild culinary skills.
Resources Foil Apple/Sultanas/Brown Sugar Cinnamon Apple Corer or Knife Tea Spoon (TSP) Fire Kit /Water/Gloves/Bucket Explanation Core the apple then put it in the middle of a square of tinfoil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bannock</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/bannock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/bannock/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever made bread? The aim of making bannock bread is to prepare, create, and cook bread over an open fire. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and develop a foundation of wild culinary skills.
Resources Plastic Food Bags (Zip Lock) A Cup Chopping Board Tea Spoon (TSP) Table Spoon (TBSP) Flour/Baking Powder/Salt/Powdered Milk/Oil or Butter/Herbs Fire Kit/Water/Gloves/Bucket Explanation Put all of these ingredients into a zip lock plastic bag; 1 cup of flour, 1 level tsp baking powder, 1/4 tsp salt, 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Bananas</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/chocolate-bananas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/chocolate-bananas/</guid>
      <description>Combining chocolate, bananas, and fire is always a good concoction that makes a great activity. The aim of making chocolate bananas is to show fruit in a different light, and how fire can help create tasty delights. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and develop a foundation of culinary skills.
Resources Chopping Board/Knife Cooking Pot/Bowls/Spoons Banana/Chocolate Buttons/Mini Marsh Mellows Foil Bin Bag Grill (if you have one) Fire Kit /Water/Gloves/Bucket Explanation Take a square of foil, then put your banana in the centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nettle Soup</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/nettle-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/nettle-soup/</guid>
      <description>Nettles have always been looked at as a weed that can sting you, so to make it into soup sounds crazy. Making nettle soup is to show that you can forage and cook your our meal in the woodland. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and develop a foundation of culinary skills.
Resources Chopping Board/Knife Cooking Pots/Sieve/Bowls/Spoons Bag/Deep Tray Scissors Fire Kit /Water/Gloves/Bucket Oil A Bag of Nettles A Large Onion, Diced 3 Potatoes, Diced 4 Celery Sticks, Diced 2 Garlic Cloves, Diced 2 Veg Stock Cubes Almond Milk Explanation Collect a bag of nettle tops (just the first 4-6 leaves) in your carrier bag or tray using the scissors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Dyes</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-dyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-dyes/</guid>
      <description>This activity combines natural materials to produce unique stained fabrics. This allows children to better understand natural dyes, their effects and their properties.
Resources Blackberries, salt, water and vinegar. Cooking pot and cup (more pots if you want to have more colours). Material (e.g. canvas). String or elastic bands. Small stones. Fire kit : water, gloves and a bucket. Explanation Mash up the blackberries in a large cooking pot (1 cup of salt to 2 cups of berries to 8 cups of water).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic Flame Pine Cones</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/magic-flame-pine-cones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/magic-flame-pine-cones/</guid>
      <description>A camp fire is a magical resource, especially if, when burning, different colours emerged from it. The aim of magic flame pine cones is to enhance story telling by creating mesmerising flames using different chemicals. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and the science behind these fantastic flames.
Resources Salt/potassium chloride/borax Bowl Water Newspaper Fire kit /water/gloves/bucket Objects (weigh down pine cones) Explanation Making Magic Flamed Pine Cones Preparing your Pine Cones Get a large bowl of water, put your pine cones in, and add in as much salt as the water will take.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cup of Tea</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/cup-of-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/cup-of-tea/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Cup of tea&amp;rsquo; is a refreshing outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of making a cup of tea is to look at producing a refreshment with fire whilst out in the woods. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and the use of fire.
Resources Fire kit /water/gloves/bucket Kelly Kettle (if trained) Tea bags/water/milk/sugar Mugs Spoons Grill (if have one) Billy can/pot Explanation The challenge is all about planning ahead, a simple activity used everyday in the urban environment could be looked at as a complex activity within the woodland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Been Drawing</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/youve-been-drawing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/youve-been-drawing/</guid>
      <description>What an opportunity for anyone to use charcoal as a pencil in creating something artistic. The aim of you&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing is to encourage our art skills and the ability to express what we want on natural materials, canvas or paper. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and the power of expression.
Resources Fire Kit/Water/Gloves/Bucket Charcoal (Ash Pencils) Paper, Card, or Canvas Explanation After having a fire use the charcoal to create observational drawings or a favourite memory of the day (make sure the charcoal is safe to touch).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire/Words/Mobile</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/fire-words-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/fire-words-mobile/</guid>
      <description>The natural television (fire) is a great way of teasing words out of your mind. &amp;lsquo;Fire/words/mobiles&amp;rsquo; aims to encourage us to think of words that can describe fire. This allows children to better understand nature and their environment and enhance there word collection.
Resources Fire Kit /Water/Gloves/Bucket Coloured Cards (Red, Yellow &amp;amp; Orange) Hole Puncher String Scissors Charcoal Explanation When the group are sitting around the fire looking at the flames, ask them what they can see, think of adjectives about the fire (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
