<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured Top on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/featured-top/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured Top on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 11:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/featured-top/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Shelters: The Top Five Techniques</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-shelters-top-five-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-shelters-top-five-techniques/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten your tent, and civilisation is hours away. Perhaps you console yourself with the romantic proposition of a beautiful night staring straight up at the unspoiled, starry sky. But no sooner have you lit a fire and picked up a good book do you realise that there&amp;rsquo;s a rain storm fast approaching!
Yes - it&amp;rsquo;s time to find out if mother nature can truly provide, and whether or not you have the resourcefulness to fashion the natural building blocks of the woodland into something robust enough to shield you from misery and failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Outdoor Learning in Schools be Compulsory?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/should-outdoor-learning-in-schools-be-compulsory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/should-outdoor-learning-in-schools-be-compulsory/</guid>
      <description>If you had to choose between an education that offered your children an enjoyable learning experience that improved their social skills and made them generally happier and healthier, or one that didn&amp;rsquo;t, which would you choose?
If, that same educational experience were to improve the health and well-being of the teachers teaching your child, improve their job satisfaction and had a positive impact on their teaching practice, would you make that educational experience compulsory?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ultimate Beginners Guide to Paddlesports</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-paddlesports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 20:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-paddlesports/</guid>
      <description>Are you feeling that there is something missing from you&amp;rsquo;re life? Do you enjoy activities that take you out of your comfort zone? If challenging yourself is something that would interest you, then why not try paddlesports?
In the UK, ‘paddlesports’ is the collective term for all paddling disciplines. In each of these watersports the paddler sits or stands on a board or vessel.
Beginners start paddling on flat water (lake or swimming pool) to develop basic skills, this helps them learn better control of their boat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Learning Explained</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</guid>
      <description>For many years people have enjoyed embracing the natural environment. Playing in fields until tea time was the norm. Nowadays, our society doesn&amp;rsquo;t engage with nature as it used too. There have been companies, through the years, delivering outdoor experiences, but is this enough?
In this article, we will look at how new evidence and practises have altered society&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the importance of the outdoors. How the term outdoor learning, has been coined, and why our society should be embracing the outdoors on a wide scale, within their daily lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moss Graffiti: Dare to Try?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mossgraffitidaretotry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mossgraffitidaretotry/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to create art with natural materials? Moss art or moss graffiti is a safe, interactive and enjoyable activity for families, schools and groups. This guide will show you different ways of using moss to have fun and reconnect with nature.
What we cover in this guide:
 the origins of ‘moss graffiti’ the development of moss graffiti, as an art form different types of moss graffiti; and how easy it is to get into creating art with moss.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
