<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sensory on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/sensory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sensory on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:27:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/sensory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scavenger Hunt</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/scavenger-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/scavenger-hunt/</guid>
      <description>Hunting for different objects is a joyous outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of a scavenger hunt is to collect natural materials, which are based around the senses. This allows children to better understand nature, the environment and develop their explorative skills.
Resources Bag Explanation The scavenger hunt can be run by asking the group to pick up specific items e.g. find 3 different leaves or find a smooth stick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust Walk</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/trust-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/trust-walk/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Trust walk&amp;rsquo; is a fun-loving outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of a trust walk is to combine natural materials to create a unique route in the mind. This allows children to better understand their senses and develop a good foundation of trust in others.
Resources Blindfolds Explanation Partner up and choose who will be blindfolded first. The guide will then take the blindfolded group member around the area and make sure that they stop and feel features like shrubs and trees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is it?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/what-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/what-is-it/</guid>
      <description>This activity is a classic game that is played by all, suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of what is it, is to blend natural materials together to produce a unique sensory activity. This allows children to better understand natural objects and intensify their senses.
Resources Draw String Bag Range of Natural Objects Explanation Collecting a range of natural objects like; a pine cone, a twig, a conker, a feather, a leaf, some mosh, a snail shell, or a stone, and putting them into a draw string bag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hand Scents</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hand-scents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hand-scents/</guid>
      <description>Suitable for young children of all abilities, this great icebreaker will help you to smell a range of different scents and interact with each other, within the group. The aim of hand scents is to combine unique aromas with others within your group. This allows children to better understand their group and how to distinguish between different scents.
Resources Cloth Squares Perfumes/Oils Explanation Using different perfumes, put a dab on each person’s hand or on a small square of cloth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Postcards</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/sound-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/sound-postcards/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Sound postcards&amp;rsquo; is a calming and thoughtful outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of sound postcards is to focus the mind and listen out for sounds around the area. This allows children to better understand nature, the environment, and to express their ability to sit and listen.
Resources Postcards Pencils Explanation Show the group how to pull an imaginary veil over their heads. This is a veil of silence and when they are wearing it, they must not speak or make a sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blindfold Shapes</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/blindfold-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/blindfold-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Can you make shapes using a rope? This team related outdoor activity will push your communication teamwork skills. The aim of blindfold shapes is to focus only on the ability to listen to others and feel where the group want to go due to the connection of the team when creating a shape. This allows children to better understand each other and also have empathy with others who have lost their sight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mud Pit</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/mud-pit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/mud-pit/</guid>
      <description>Get messy in this fun outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of a mud pit is to combine natural materials to produce a unique play area. This allows children the freedom to use their imagination, creativity, and senses within the natural world.
Resources Water Bucket Toys (cars/soldiers/animals) Explanation Make a mud pit by pouring a lot of water on a soiled area or wait until a storm has been.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop &amp; Listen</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/stop-listen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/stop-listen/</guid>
      <description>This activity will help you unwind as you will be focusing on sounds around you. The aim of stop and listen is to focus your mind on particular natural sounds. This allows children to have a better appreciation of the natural world.
Explanation Unless we make time to listen to the sounds, many of them will be lost into the background. If you listen carefully, you might be able to hear; the flapping of a swallow, the drumming of a woodpecker, the rustle of a breeze through the trees, the trickle of a stream, a falling leaf landing on the ground, or even the popping of seed cases in the sunshine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find your Tree</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/find-your-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/find-your-tree/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Find your tree&amp;rsquo; will give you the opportunity to focus on your senses. The aim of finding your tree is cooperation and trust with others to find your tree. This allows children to better understand their senses and develop a good foundation of trust in others.
Resources Blindfolds Explanation Divide the group into pairs or threes. One member of the group is blindfolded and are led by their peer/s to a tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smelly Cocktails</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/smelly-cocktails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/smelly-cocktails/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Smelly cocktails&amp;rsquo; is a playful outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of smelly cocktails is to combine natural materials to produce unique aromas. This allows children to better understand nature and the environment and to express their creativity.
Resources Stick/Spoon Plastic Cup/Mug Natural Materials Explanation Pour a little bit of water into a clear plastic cup and add fallen petals, natural herbs, leaves or wild fruits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
