<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Code of conduct&amp;rsquo; is the foundation when performing activities within the natural environment. This page focuses on how to act within a natural space. It is important the group know at the start of their session how to act and respect the natural space.
Entering the woodland We will all be respectful of this great resource as we explore and play within it, but know that when we enter, we are entering the home of many different creatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equipment Guidance</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/equipment-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/equipment-guidance/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Equipment guidance&amp;rsquo; gives you an idea on what a leader may need when taking their group further afield. They will have to be aware of the group&amp;rsquo;s needs, different activities delivered, and know the environment in which these activities will take place. It can be a daunting task having to decide on particular equipment, which is why this page is here. Leader&amp;rsquo;s bag The leader is responsible for providing a safe environment for the group to work in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accident and Emergency Guidance</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/accident-and-emergency-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/accident-and-emergency-guidance/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Accident and emergency guidance&amp;rsquo; is essential to anyone whether indoors or out. The aim of this list is to help you have the confidence to know how to deal with a stressed situation, and also to make it clear on what information needs to be available for relevant parties. Whether you already have your own guidance, or whether you are new to this idea, it is important to be open to the information below as you might have missed a step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/about/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, children in the UK spend much, if not most, of their time indoors watching TV, using the internet or sitting in classrooms. Little time is spent interacting with the world around them. We believe that this lack of outdoor exploration may be impacting not only on their ability to learn and retain data, but also their mental health  .
New research  in this field has shown that outdoor learning  has made children happier, healthier, and more motivated to learn, and therefore it is important for schools to integrate this form of teaching within their curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/contribute/</guid>
      <description>A volunteer-run (no-one gets paid) project known as outlearn has been created to help schools and families, in supporting the younger generation through their formative years.
We are always on the look-out for skilled writers (with experience) who share our beliefs. Please read our &amp;lsquo;About  &amp;rsquo; page. If you still want to write for us, drop us an email (email address in the footer) and include links to your previous works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This website (outlearn) is provided as a volunteer-run project for schools and families that wish to support the future generation in understanding and benefiting from being in the natural environment. We do not intend to sell or distribute anyone&amp;rsquo;s data as this does not align to our goals.
The below information sets out how outlearn uses and protects the data collected via our website.
When using this site, you are legally bound to the following privacy policy, so please read carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Nest Box on a Budget</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/pallet-wood-nest-boxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 22:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/pallet-wood-nest-boxes/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that with just a few materials, you can help birds thrive within your area by creating nesting boxes? This guide will help you look at how you can create a nest box at a low cost.
‌With the cold, dark days of winter becoming warmer and brighter, signs of spring are becoming more abundant. One of these signs are sounds of birds returning to our gardens and woodlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Spaces in Schools: Is the Government Doing Enough?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</guid>
      <description>Just a single encounter with the natural world can be a powerful and life-affirming event. Its innate beauty can inform our sense of purpose and significance, as well as capturing our respective imaginations.
With our growing appreciation for the natural world, it’s no wonder that the National Trust recently saw record numbers of visitors in excess of 26.6m  .
However, the outdoors aren’t just for adults. They can also play a profound role in the development and positive mental health of children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide To Creating An Effective Outdoor Learning Space</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/creating-an-effective-outdoor-learning-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 19:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/creating-an-effective-outdoor-learning-space/</guid>
      <description>The outdoors has proven to be an effective learning environment for children, but, for teachers and parents with little experience teaching in this environment, it may be confusing to get started. In this guide, we will address this issue and show you how to select and create the perfect outdoor learning space.
Words Matter According to recent reports  , the terms &amp;ldquo;Outdoor Learning  &amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Forest School&amp;rdquo; are becoming more popular, and those who have explored these avenues have learned how much this form of learning engages and motivates young children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Shelters: The Top Five Techniques</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-shelters-top-five-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-shelters-top-five-techniques/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten your tent, and civilisation is hours away. Perhaps you console yourself with the romantic proposition of a beautiful night staring straight up at the unspoiled, starry sky. But no sooner have you lit a fire and picked up a good book do you realise that there&amp;rsquo;s a rain storm fast approaching!
Yes - it&amp;rsquo;s time to find out if mother nature can truly provide, and whether or not you have the resourcefulness to fashion the natural building blocks of the woodland into something robust enough to shield you from misery and failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Has Our Culture Changed the way we Play?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/has-our-culture-changed-the-way-we-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 16:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/has-our-culture-changed-the-way-we-play/</guid>
      <description>30 years ago, many children would stay outside all day, playing and exploring, only to return when it was time for their dinner. The world we now live in is very different to the world back then. Studies  have shown that since 2015, that one in nine children haven&amp;rsquo;t visited woodlands, parks, and beaches, and this is down to a number of factors. In this article we are going to investigate these factors and their impact towards play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosscaping: Ready for the Challenge?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mosscaping-ready-for-the-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mosscaping-ready-for-the-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Fancy the challenge of transforming an unwanted area outside, into a vibrant natural space for both yourself and living invertebrates to appreciate? If so then get your coat and boots on, get outside, get creative, most of all, have fun.
What is mosscaping? Mosscaping is where you use moss  to change the look of an area. It could act as natural cover for areas that at too damp and shady for other plant life to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Preventable Disorder is Destroying our Children&#39;s Future</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/this-preventable-disorder-is-destroying-our-childrens-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/this-preventable-disorder-is-destroying-our-childrens-future/</guid>
      <description>Are less children experiencing outdoor environments? This article talks about why children don&amp;rsquo;t play outside in today&amp;rsquo;s society and due to this could be labelled with having &amp;rsquo;nature deficit disorder&amp;rsquo; (NDD).
NDD was coined by Richard Louv (American author) in his book, &amp;lsquo;Last Child in the Woods&amp;rsquo;  to highlight the problem he sees for young children today, and for their level of experience within natural environments, locally or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Outdoor Learning in Schools be Compulsory?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/should-outdoor-learning-in-schools-be-compulsory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/should-outdoor-learning-in-schools-be-compulsory/</guid>
      <description>If you had to choose between an education that offered your children an enjoyable learning experience that improved their social skills and made them generally happier and healthier, or one that didn&amp;rsquo;t, which would you choose?
If, that same educational experience were to improve the health and well-being of the teachers teaching your child, improve their job satisfaction and had a positive impact on their teaching practice, would you make that educational experience compulsory?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There a Place for the Hidden Curriculum in Educational Settings?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/is-the-hidden-curriculum-starting-to-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 14:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/is-the-hidden-curriculum-starting-to-show/</guid>
      <description>Educational establishments, even though the focus is still on pupils passing their subject tests, teachers have become more aware of the importance of the hidden skills that children learn alongside these subjects. This article will look into why these hidden skills are very important.
With employers screaming out for soft skills such as grit, resilience, self-mastery and communication, clearly academic achievement is no longer enough. Despite the importance of the curriculum at all education settings, the teaching of softer skills are becoming more of a priority to young people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ultimate Beginners Guide to Paddlesports</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-paddlesports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 20:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-paddlesports/</guid>
      <description>Are you feeling that there is something missing from you&amp;rsquo;re life? Do you enjoy activities that take you out of your comfort zone? If challenging yourself is something that would interest you, then why not try paddlesports?
In the UK, ‘paddlesports’ is the collective term for all paddling disciplines. In each of these watersports the paddler sits or stands on a board or vessel.
Beginners start paddling on flat water (lake or swimming pool) to develop basic skills, this helps them learn better control of their boat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Learning Explained</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</guid>
      <description>For many years people have enjoyed embracing the natural environment. Playing in fields until tea time was the norm. Nowadays, our society doesn&amp;rsquo;t engage with nature as it used too. There have been companies, through the years, delivering outdoor experiences, but is this enough?
In this article, we will look at how new evidence and practises have altered society&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the importance of the outdoors. How the term outdoor learning, has been coined, and why our society should be embracing the outdoors on a wide scale, within their daily lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Essential English Walks</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-essential-english-walks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 13:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-essential-english-walks/</guid>
      <description>Walking for pleasure has been a much beloved pastime since the birth of civilisation, and can have great health benefits. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking for some slow-pace, low-impact exercise, or an excuse to get out of the house and gather your thoughts, walking is readily available just about anywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s even good for digestion!
But what if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to step up your walking game and only the most picturesque walks will do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build an Inclusive PE Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-to-build-an-inclusive-pe-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-to-build-an-inclusive-pe-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>Moving from mainstream to special educational needs (SEN), the learning curve can feel like quite a jump. This article is aimed at teachers within primary education or secondary PE. It introduces SEN and talks about creating an inclusive PE curriculum, which is accessible for all learners. It explores taking skills from traditional games and explains how to teach them in natural environments, for a more inclusive PE lesson.
Types of SEN  SEN covers a vast spectrum of learning difficulties, which can include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Outdoor Awards that Help Guide Schools to a Better Future</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-outdoor-awards-that-help-guide-schools-to-a-better-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-outdoor-awards-that-help-guide-schools-to-a-better-future/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find awards that will benefit your school? This article shows five different outdoor related awards that will help transform your school for the better. Each award, in this article, will give you a summary of what their award is all about. This will give you a good understanding of whether your school is presently ready to taken on that particular award or not.
Giving children the opportunity to experience these awards, can help not just them but their local community, which will in turn help lead to the awareness of preserving the natural environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Gardening Help our Schools?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/can-gardening-help-our-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 11:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/can-gardening-help-our-schools/</guid>
      <description>This article talks about why the Royal Horticultural Society (RHS) developed an award for schools, and expresses the importance it holds for every child in education. It also breaks up the award, so it can be seen what is involved and why it is a valuable award to have in schools.
In 2007, RHS launched their campaign for school gardening as a result of the government&amp;rsquo;s proposals to change and improve child care, which was known as the &amp;lsquo;Every Child Matters  &amp;rsquo; programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Woodland Trust is Helping our Schools</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-the-woodland-trust-is-helping-our-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 21:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-the-woodland-trust-is-helping-our-schools/</guid>
      <description>This article explains how the woodland trust&amp;rsquo;s award for schools can help teachers inspire and educate their pupils around creating and sustaining our plant. It also breaks down the award, to make it easier to understand what each part consists of.
The Woodland Trust has devised a great award that schools can adopt for free. It was created as a project in 2008 and has helped children learn about and be inspired by trees, woods and wildlife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UN&#39;s Global Scheme to Protect our Environment</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/the-uns-global-scheme-to-protect-our-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 10:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/the-uns-global-scheme-to-protect-our-environment/</guid>
      <description>Have you heard of the Eco-Schools award? This article talks about why it was created, the importance of it and how schools can get involved.
In 1992, as a result of the UN conferences on environment and development, people at the conference felt that the only way forward in protecting the plant was to engage the youth of today. Since 1994, Foundation for Environmental Education  (FEE) have run the Eco-Schools programme globally to carry out the UN&amp;rsquo;s wishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Award to Help Pupils with Special Educational Needs</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-award-to-help-pupils-with-special-educational-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 14:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-award-to-help-pupils-with-special-educational-needs/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find an award that can help challenge special educational needs (SEN) pupils or even help bridge the gap from primary to secondary school? This article explains what the award is, why you should value it, a breakdown of the award and how to get involved.
The Junior Award Scheme for Schools (JASS) is owned and distributed by Friends of The Award  in Edinburgh and the Lothians (FOTA). This scheme is a holistic accredited learning programme for children and young people aged 5 – 14 years, which also works really well in an additional needs setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with The Duke of Edinburgh&#39;s Award</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/getting-started-with-the-duke-of-edinburghs-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 17:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/getting-started-with-the-duke-of-edinburghs-award/</guid>
      <description>In 1956, Prince Philip, The Duke of Edinburgh, created an award to help children and young adults gain vital life skills that are essential within today&amp;rsquo;s modern society. This article will explain how Prince Philip came up with the idea, and why it is essential for young people up to 25 years old. Also, it will explain the breakdown of the award, and how to get involved as a participants or leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Awards that can Help Students Move Forward</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 14:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-awards/</guid>
      <description>The UK&amp;rsquo;s education system works around academic achievements. Not all students are academic, which is why having extra awards added to their records of achievement (curriculum vitae) will show future employers that they are capable, and therefore deserve to be considered. In this article, it will talk about three outdoor awards that students can achieve. Helping them to develop a multitude of life skills, which will prepare them for life&amp;rsquo;s challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Insight into Sir Isaac Newton</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-insight-into-sir-isaac-newton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 20:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-insight-into-sir-isaac-newton/</guid>
      <description>Sir Isaac Newton was a genius and his discoveries are the foundation of a lot of scientific and maths theories. This theme focuses on one of his discoveries, which was &amp;lsquo;universal gravitation (gravity).
The Walk Go for a walk around the area you wish to carry out the activities. Talk about Sir Isaac Newton and ask your group, what they might know about him. If they don&amp;rsquo;t know then talk about gravity, laws of motion, and rainbows (refraction of light).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a Bug&#39;s Life</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/its-a-bugs-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 21:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/its-a-bugs-life/</guid>
      <description>What different types of creatures live in and around your area. You will focus on making a bug in both a physical form and picture. You will figure out what type of bugs live in your area, provide food for it and build a home for it too.
Your Favourite Bug   Do you have a favourite bug? What is it called? Create your bug using natural materials.
Bug Print   Make your masterpiece by using natural materials and paint, and then press the painted materials onto the paper to create your favourite bug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of the Hidden Trident</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/in-search-of-the-hidden-trident/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 18:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/in-search-of-the-hidden-trident/</guid>
      <description>Your group are mermaids/mermens and they are trying to find the hidden trident. Only the trident will help them find the secret cave of Neptune. On your travels, you will see your friend Tallulah the turtle, who will help you in your quest to find the hidden trident.
The Walk Go for a walk around the area you wish to carry out the activities. Talk about mythical creatures and ask your group what they might think they would look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Risk Assessments</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/daily-risk-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 21:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/daily-risk-assessments/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Daily risk assessments&amp;rsquo; (DRAs) let the reader know of present hazards, which have either been dealt with or not. DRAs are active risk assessment forms, which need to be consulted and updated for new hazards on any particular site.
Download our Daily Risk Assessment  Completing a DRA This form is for anyone who has noticed a hazard in and around the site. If you see a new hazard then write it down on the DRA form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Topics to Consider Before Leading an Outdoor Activity</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/10-topics-to-consider-before-leading-an-outdoor-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 23:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/10-topics-to-consider-before-leading-an-outdoor-activity/</guid>
      <description>Do you feel that you could be missing out on essential information that can help you and your group have fun and safe experiences outside? This article mentions ten topics, which will help you to create a safe and solid outdoor activities.
Before leading an outdoor activity, there are a number of things to consider that will benefit individual experiences. Below are ten areas that will help you keep your group happy and safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Scenic Cycle Routes in England</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/scenic-cycle-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/scenic-cycle-routes/</guid>
      <description>Cycling can be a purely functional activity - allowing us to commute to and from work, visit friends or collect our groceries. Cycling for pleasure can provide us with an entirely different, much more fulfilling experience.
The physical effort that we put in to cycling is great for our bodily health; it offers aerobic exercise without the social awkwardness of a gym as well as the ability to strengthen our leg muscles, abdominals and glutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding on a Session</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/safeguarding-on-a-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/safeguarding-on-a-session/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Safeguarding on a session&amp;rsquo; is an essential part in helping to keep members of the group safe from themselves, their team, and others external to the group. Every adult has to understand and be aware of what issues young or older people can be faced with. This page focuses on the leader having a responsibility in relation to child protection and also knowing the aims and how to approach the situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equal Opportunities &amp; Inclusion within a Session</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/equal-opportunities-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/equal-opportunities-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Equal opportunities &amp;amp; inclusion within a session&amp;rsquo; is important to be aware of. Everyone can learn in different ways, and the leader should be mindful that the group can have a range of different abilities. This will ensure that every member of the group will have a quality experience.
It is also important within each session to allow every member the opportunity of achieving the highest standards, regardless of ethnicity, religion, age, disability, gender, or background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide to using a Kettle</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/guide-to-using-a-kettle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 23:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/guide-to-using-a-kettle/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Guide to using a kettle&amp;rsquo; is an important skill to learn and will ensure the you use your kettle safely.
The Ghillie kettle and the Kelly kettle are very similar products. There are some slight differences but they achieve the same goal, which is to boil water. The Ghillie Kettle  is made in the UK, whereas the Kelly Kettle  is made in America.
Clearing your area Make sure you have a clear surface when preparing your fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide to Fire Making</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/guide-to-fire-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 23:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/guide-to-fire-making/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Guide to fire making&amp;rsquo; is a great skill to learn, as it will help you achieve a number of activities. This guide is to help you make and manage your fire safely. Also by creating and managing your fire with good practise, you are showing your group how it is supposed to be performed safely.
Clearing your area Make sure you have a clear surface when preparing your fire. This reduces the risk of setting fire to other parts of a woodland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/networking/</guid>
      <description>Home  &amp;gt; Outdoor activities  &amp;gt; Nature-Based Activities  &amp;gt; Maths-Focused Activities  &amp;gt; Contingency Activities  &amp;gt; Networking
&amp;lsquo;Networking&amp;rsquo; in life is a brilliant way to get to know others, also in this activity as well. The aim of networking is to find people who you have a link with. This allows children to better understand themselves, their environment, and how to ask the right questions.
Explanation Everyone is standing and waiting for the leader to start the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Person Standing</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/last-person-standing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/last-person-standing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Last person standing&amp;rsquo; is a playful outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of last person standing is to not get tug. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment, and how to follow the rules of a game.
Resources  Stopwatch  Explanation A variation on tig but instead of one person being on, everyone is on. The idea is to survive till you are the only one playing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matchbox Nose Race</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/matchbox-nose-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/matchbox-nose-race/</guid>
      <description>Get ready for a very different type of race, one which you will have to not only use your legs but your nose too. The aim of matchbox nose race is to compete against others in a unique way. This allows children to better understand their environment, their technique, and how to follow the rules of a game.
Resources  Matchboxes Stopwatch Measuring Tape Blindfolds  Explanation Create a track, generally the size of a hall, or create the track size to your exact room measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find a New Chair</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/find-a-new-chair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 20:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/find-a-new-chair/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Find a new chair&amp;rsquo; is a unique ice breaker that will let you get to know your peers even more. The aim of find a new chair is to find out about your team members. This allows children to better understand their environment, their questioning skills and how to listen.
Resources  Chairs  Explanation Get your group to find a chair and make a circle (facing inward). One person stands in the middle of the circle and starts the game by saying a statement that is true to themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ruler of Rulers</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-ruler-of-rulers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 20:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-ruler-of-rulers/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;The ruler of rulers&amp;rsquo; need to be alert and focused on the numbers in order to stay at the top. The aim of the ruler of rulers is about concentration and reactions. This allows children to better understand their environment, their listening skills and how to follow the rules of a game.
Resources  Chairs  Explanation Each person has a chair, line them up in a line facing one side, making it easier for the group to count each other off (or two lines facing inward/half circle/whole circle to change the way the group have to count each other off).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cups!</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/cups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 20:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/cups/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Cups&amp;rsquo; is a energetic indoor/outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of cups is to try and beat the other team by turning over the cups to your designated side. This allows children to better understand strategy, their environment, and how to work well with your team.
Resources  Plastic cups x 40+ Stopwatch  Explanation Stage one Split group into two teams, team ‘ups’ and team ‘downs’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human - What&#39;s Missing?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/human-whats-missing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 20:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/human-whats-missing/</guid>
      <description>You have to be alert and aware when trying to play this superb activity. The aim of human - what&amp;rsquo;s missing? is to pick out who has gone from the picture. This allows children to better understand their environment, and how follow focus on their memory.
Resources  Large Sheet/Tarp  Explanation Just like the game ‘what’s missing’, where you have objects on a tray. Someone has to try and remember all the objects and then one, two or three items are removed and that person then tries and remembers what&amp;rsquo;s missing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Seconds - Hide and Seek</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/10-seconds-hide-and-seek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 18:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/10-seconds-hide-and-seek/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;10 seconds - hide and seek&amp;rsquo; is a brilliant indoor/outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of 10 seconds - hide and seek is to find all the hiders but only in a short time period. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment, and how follow the rules of a game.
Resources  Stopwatch  Explanation This game is the standard hide and seek game but you only have ten seconds to try and find everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>45 Seconds</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/45-seconds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 18:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/45-seconds/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;45 Seconds&amp;rsquo; is a different outlook on the game dodge ball. The aim of 45 seconds is to work in pairs and not get caught by a ball. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment, and learn how to work well in pairs.
Resources  Timer Soft Ball  Explanation The group splits up into pairs. They select who they want to pitch, and the pitcher rolls the ball to the pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wave - Hide and Seek</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wave-hide-and-seek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wave-hide-and-seek/</guid>
      <description>This adaptation has revamped the classic game of hide and seek. The aim of wave - hide and seek is to find all the hiders. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment, and how to follow the rules of a game.
Resources  Rope (or use sticks)  Explanation The group creates a circle or assigns a designated area. A seeker is chosen and the rest go to hide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hungry Creatures</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hungry-creatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 23:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hungry-creatures/</guid>
      <description>Everyone gets hungry, even bugs, so why not try and help them with their food shop. The aim of hungry creatures is to work out how much food to give to the creatures within the area your looking. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and how to create a tally chart.
Resources  Pencil/Ruler/Paper  Explanation Get into pairs and find specific areas to conduct your search. Find different types of creatures and record them on a tally chart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leafy Leaves</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/leafy-leaves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 23:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/leafy-leaves/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Leafy leaves&amp;rsquo; is a great way of collecting all different types of leaves and really looking and understanding them. The aim of leafy leaves is to combine nature and graphs. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and how to create a tally chart.
Resources  Pencil/Ruler/Paper Bags or Buckets  Explanation How many leaves can you find within the woodland. Before you go out, make a prediction of what kind of leaves you will see, and record these predictions on a chart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spikey by Nature</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/spikey-by-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 22:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/spikey-by-nature/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Spikey by nature&amp;rsquo; is a joyful outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of spikey by nature is to collect many different types of leaves and count their spikes. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment, and how to create Carroll diagrams.
Resources  Pencil/Ruler/Paper  Explanation How many leaves can you find within the woodland. Use the Carroll diagram to record your findings. Use the diagram below to give you a head start (for lower abilities use other diagrams eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Under Here?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/whats-under-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 22:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/whats-under-here/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered what lives under logs and leaves? The aim of what&amp;rsquo;s under here is to combine nature and graphs. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and how to create a pictograph.
Resources  Pencil/Ruler/Paper  Explanation Your group could equally use tally charts, bar charts etc. Instead of using pencils and paper to record your pictograph, why not use an ‘Ash pencil’  and a piece of wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many steps?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/how-many-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/how-many-steps/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;How many steps?&amp;rsquo; gets people to come together to estimate distances. The aim of this activity is to count steps and use that figure to try and estimate a number of steps needed to reach a fixed point in the distance. This encourages children to predict distances.
Resources  Paper/Pen Blindfolds  Explanation Give the group a place to walk to. Before they start to walk to that designated place, they have to try and work out how many steps it will take.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number Swap</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/number-swap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/number-swap/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Number Swap&amp;rsquo; is a team oriented outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of number swap is to understand where numbers have to be and order them correctly. This allows children to listen to each other and work closely with others.
Resources  Numbered Vests (optional) Numbered Log Discs (optional)  Explanation Each member of the group is given a number (numbered vest/log disc). They all get into a line, and reorder themselves into the correct position depending on their number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treasure Hunt Counting</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/treasure-hunt-counting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/treasure-hunt-counting/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Treasure hunt counting&amp;rsquo; is a variation on scavenger hunt. The aim of treasure hunt counting is to match numbers with natural materials. This allows children to respect nature, the environment, and focus on materials not numbers.
Resources  White marker paint pens Chalk Number logs (optional)  Explanation When hunting for treasure within the natural environment, you will need to try and match your numbers. This means that if your number is for example five, you will have to think of a natural item that you can find five of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting Stick</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/counting-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/counting-stick/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Counting stick&amp;rsquo; will really help improve your number skills. The aim of this session is to use a stick to illustrate where certain numbers should be placed. This allows children to understand how to count up/down at any point.
Resources  Scissors Paper/Pen String  Explanation First find a stick, then tell the group that one end of the stick starts at zero and the other ends at ten (pick different ranges depending on their ability).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinnamon Sugar Doughnuts</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/cinnamon-sugar-doughnuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/cinnamon-sugar-doughnuts/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Cinnamon sugar doughnuts&amp;rsquo; are very tasty to eat, they are even satisfying to make too. The aim of cinnamon sugar doughnuts is to make doughnuts by following a recipe. This allows children to read the recipe and work out the value for each ingredient.
Resources  Fire Kit/Water Buttermilk biscuit dough (refrigerated/cool) Vegetable oil 3/4 cup sugar 1/2 teaspoon cinnamon  Plain Glaze (optional):  2 cups confectioners sugar 1/4 teaspoon salt 8 tablespoons unsalted butter (melted) 1/4 cup milk 1 teaspoon vanilla extract  Explanation On a cutting board, separate the buttermilk biscuit  dough and use the vegetable oil cap to cut a hole in the biscuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Style Buttermilk Biscuits</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/american-style-buttermilk-biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/american-style-buttermilk-biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Following a recipe can be tricky but creating something from numbers and instructions can be really satisfying. The aim of this activity is to make biscuits by following a recipe. This makes children read the recipe and work out the value for each ingredient.
Resources  Fire kit/Gloves/Water (Bucket) Waxed Paper/Biscuit Cutter/Butter Brush 250g plain flour 4 teaspoons baking powder 1/4 teaspoon bicarbonate of soda 1/2 teaspoon salt 2 tablespoons cold butter 2 tablespoons vegetable fat 230ml chilled buttermilk (or natural yogurt (thinned) with whole milk) 50g butter, melted (optional)  Explanation Combine all ingredients, then knead the dough by hand until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number Logs</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/number-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/number-logs/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Number logs&amp;rsquo; uses natural materials and crosses them with numbers. The aim of number logs is to use your sawing and counting skills. This allows children to better understand how to use tools safely and efficiently, and also gives them the opportunity to create numbers in a more tangible way.
Resources  Logs/Hand Saw/Safety Gloves Paint/Chalk Board Paint (CBP) Chalk  Explanation Collect logs from the nature environment, and use the saw to create thin discs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunt for Natural Colours</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hunt-for-natural-colours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hunt-for-natural-colours/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Hunt for natural colours&amp;rsquo; is a superb outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of hunt for natural colours is to use your hunting and counting skills. This allows children to better understand where to try and find items and gives them the opportunity to count for a purpose.
Resources  Paint (different colours) Paint Brushes Paper Pencils  Explanation Get natural objects (sticks, leaves, stones etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Quantities</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-quantities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-quantities/</guid>
      <description>The woodland has loads of resources for you to create great quantities in either the soil, or on top of the soil. The aim of natural quantities is look into two activities; &amp;lsquo;show me&amp;rsquo; and fraction wall. This allows children to better understand quantities and also shows them how to represent a number in a different way.
Explanation Show Me Call out a number to your team and make them create that number by either drawing a tally chart, drawing a number (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavenger Hunt</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/scavenger-hunt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/scavenger-hunt-2/</guid>
      <description>Discovering a new place could be done by exploring for certain items. The aim of scavenger hunt is to use your hunting and counting skills. This allows children to better understand where to try and find items and gives them the opportunity to count for a purpose.
Resources  Bags  Explanation The scavenger hunt can be run by asking the group to pick up specific items e.g. find 3 different leaves or find 1 smooth barked tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Javelin</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-javelin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-javelin/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Natural javelin&amp;rsquo; is a creative outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of natural javelin is to combine your creative skills and the natural environment. This allows children to better understand nature, the environment, and how to use tools properly.
Resources  Different Sized ‘Woodland Based’ Javelins Knife, Scissors, Feathers, Thick/Thin Cord, Superglue, Marker Pen Tape Measure/Distance Measuring Wheel  Explanation Find natural javelins within the woodland and create a throwing area, by creating a throwing line with markers every 5/10 metres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are we nearly there yet?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/are-we-nearly-there-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/are-we-nearly-there-yet/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Are we nearly there yet?&amp;rsquo; looks at trust and the ability to estimate. The aim of this activity is to trust your partner and guess how long it will take to complete the course. This allows children to better understand how to predict a journey.
Resources  Stopwatch Ropes Blind Folds  Explanation Plan a route within the woodland that goes under, over and even around objects. Get the group to guess how long it will take to complete the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burn, Burn, Burn</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/burn-burn-burn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/burn-burn-burn/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered if that feather or leaf will burn? This activity will show you what burns, and for how long. The aim of burn, burn, burn is to try to estimate how long it takes different materials to burn. This allows children to better understand the structure of different types of materials.
Resources  Fire Kit/Gloves/Water Different items to burn (E.g. biscuit, grass, feather) Stopwatch Pencil/Ruler/Paper  Explanation Find different items that your group wish to burn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/tracking/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to follow a route that was made by one of your peers? The aim of tracking is to come up with natural signs that will help guide someone through your chosen path. This allows children to better understand how to create signs from natural materials and makes them aware of how many different signals there are.
Resources  Natural Materials Tape Measure/Distance Measuring Wheel  Explanation Get group to make a number of natural signs (left/right/forward/finish).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storyboard Shapes</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/storyboard-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 19:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/storyboard-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Telling a story using sticks and other natural materials might be fun, but making an the characters into shapes in mind blowing. The aim of storyboard shapes is to use your imagination and artistic flare. This allows children to better understand how to make shapes to tell a story.
Explanation Split the group into two or more teams. Each team thinks of a well-known story e.g. Jack and the Beanstalk, The Bear Hunt or The Stickman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Shapes</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hidden-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 18:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hidden-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Shapes are everywhere, all you need is to become more aware of you environment. The aim of hidden shapes is to first train your eyes to focus on shapes on a grid then to turn it to natural hidden shapes. This allows children to find shapes in a grid or within the natural environment.
Resources  Rope  Explanation Shape Grid Groups or pairs are to collect rope, Ivy or homemade cordage (made from nettles) and make patterns on the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Symmetry</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-symmetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 17:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-symmetry/</guid>
      <description>Can you find symmetry within the natural world. The aim of this activity is to find natural material and use a mirror to investigate whether they have symmetry or not. This allows children to better understand how to look for symmetrical items in the natural environment.
Resources  Mirrors Scissors  Explanation In pairs, find leaves or other natural materials and place a mirror at 90 degrees at the mid point on the natural object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nangles</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/nangles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 16:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/nangles/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Nangles&amp;rsquo; enlightens people on how many angles they are within the natural world. The aim of nangles is to combine the use of natural materials with maths. This allows children to better understand angles and the natural environment.
Resources  Protractor String Sticks Scissors  Explanation Before setting out into the woodland or your local area, get two sticks and tie them together (sheer lashing  ). The sticks can be any size, but it is felt that the smaller the sticks are the easier it is to walk with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Kite</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-kite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 18:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-kite/</guid>
      <description>Kite making requires mathematical skills, resources, and determination to create a functioning kit. The aim of making a kite is to use your initiative and artistic flare. This allows children to better understand how to make a symmetrical kite out of a number of materials.
Resources  Plastic Bag (or paper) Sticky Tape Wooden Skewers x 2 String Ribbon Scissors  Explanation Diamond Kite  Create and cut out your diamond shape Size up two wooden skewers, (using the diamond shape as a template) tie together at mid-point to make a cross Pierce four holes on each corner and thread string through each of the holes, attaching wooden skewers to the diamond shape, making sure you leave excess on top for the ribbon (if you want) Tie a piece of string from the left corner to the right corner (horizontally), and attach another piece of string on the mid-point, make sure you have a lot as this is your ‘flying line’ To finish, attach ribbon to left, right and bottom corners  Other kites you might want to try making are known as;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bug Hotel</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/bug-hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 23:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/bug-hotel/</guid>
      <description>Creating a place that helps all types of bugs and others creatures is a lovely way to help re-home them. The aim of bug hotel is to combine natural materials into a home for all little creatures. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express their creativity.
Resources  Pallets Rocks/Stones/Bricks/Slab Pine Cones/Dead Wood/Dry Leaves Elder Stems Chicken Wire/Wire Cutters Spade Hammer/Small Fencing Staples  Explanation The bug hotel is a collection of the bee B&amp;amp;B  , deadwood den  , pine cone palace  , and rock retreat  .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock Retreat</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/rock-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 23:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/rock-retreat/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Rock retreat&amp;rsquo; is a fun outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of rock retreat is to combine natural materials into providing a home for the rock dwellers. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express their creativity.
Resources  Rocks, Concrete Slabs, Stones Bricks—Different types Blocks (Breeze blocks) Pallets Spade  Explanation A number of ways you can create your rock retreat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pine Cone Palace</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/pine-cone-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 23:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/pine-cone-palace/</guid>
      <description>Helping ladybirds and other bugs find a home is what this activity is all about. The aim of pine cone palace is to combine natural materials into a home for the little ladybirds. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express their creativity.
Resources  Pine Cones/Leaves String/Chicken Wire and Wire/or Wired Hanging Baskets Scissors (if using string)/Wire Cutters (if using chicken wire)  Explanation Gather pine cones and put them together so that they interlock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadwood Den</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/deadwood-den/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 23:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/deadwood-den/</guid>
      <description>Deadwood is an amazing resource within the woodland and helps lots of different types of bugs. The aim of deadwood den is to combine natural materials into a home for the beetles, larvae, centipedes, woodlice, and fungi. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express their creativity.
Resources  Sticks/Logs Dead Wood Punk Wood (over seasoned wood) String  Explanation Collect lots of thick sticks, different sized logs, and dried out wood (punk wood).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bee B&amp;B</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/bee-b-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 23:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/bee-b-b/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Bee B&amp;amp;B&amp;rsquo; is a lovely outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of Bee B&amp;amp;B is to combine natural materials into a home for the little bees. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express their creativity.
Resources  Hollow Stems or Elder Stems (to hollow out) Plant Pot/s (clay not plastic) Stones Wire Rod/Skewer Scissors/Secateurs  Explanation Collect lots of dried out, hollow stems and pack them into an old terracotta plant pot (a plastic one might get blown around too much).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleeping Farmers</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/sleeping-farmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 21:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/sleeping-farmers/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Sleeping farmers&amp;rsquo; is a great outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of sleeping farmers is to combine your senses and patience. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to embrace the story.
Resources  String/Blindfolds x 3 Timer  Options:
 Bring bottles Chickens (toy) Doughnuts (mud made version)  Explanation Make supplies like chickens, bottles of cider, and doughnuts. By doing this the groups have supplies to try and collect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shaping the Characters</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/shaping-the-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 21:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/shaping-the-characters/</guid>
      <description>In order to understand what the characters are feeling, you need to imagine you are one of them. The aim of shaping the characters is to gain a better understanding of what each character might be emotionally going through as the story progresses. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to embrace the story.
Resources  Paper/Pencil  Explanation Think about the characters within ‘The Fantastic Mr Fox’ story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cunning Plan</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-cunning-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 21:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-cunning-plan/</guid>
      <description>This measuring based activity will get you into the mindset of how clever and cunning the fox is. The aim of the cunning plan is to create a course that will run around all the farms. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to embrace the story.
Resources  Three Farmers (could be members or toys) Measuring Tape  Explanation Define your farm areas and make a course that will go from your lair to and around all the farms and back to your lair again (home).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tales of Robin Hood</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-tales-of-robin-hood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 21:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-tales-of-robin-hood/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the tales of Robin Hood, whereby, Robin has asked village folk if they have what it takes in becoming one of his Merries. This team are Robin Hood&amp;rsquo;s trusted steeds, who are all highly trained men and women.
The group of village folk have come to the edge of Sherwood Forest to be taken by Robin to a secret location deep in the forest, where they can train to become one of the legendary Merries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bean&#39;s Spiced Cider</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/beans-spiced-cider/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 20:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/beans-spiced-cider/</guid>
      <description>Making drinks over a fire is always a great activity, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s linked to The Fantastic Mr Fox. The aim of Bean&amp;rsquo;s spiced cider is to create a non alcoholic tasty drink. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to embrace the story.
Resources  Apple Juice/Apple/Ginger Cinnamon Sticks/Cloves Apple Corer/Knife Tea Spoon (tsp) Fire Kit  /Water/Gloves/Bucket  Explanation Preparation  3 cups unfiltered apple juice ½ apple, cut into slices 1½” inch piece of ginger, very thinly sliced 3 cinnamon sticks 15 whole cloves  Ready for activity Add all the ingredients into a small pot or saucepan on the fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bunce&#39;s Special Doughnuts</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/bunces-special-doughnuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 20:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/bunces-special-doughnuts/</guid>
      <description>This activity is creative, messy and very fun, with a hint of scavenging of supplies. The aim of Bunce&amp;rsquo;s special doughnuts is to use the natural materials to create a unique doughnut. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to embrace the story.
Explanation Bunce, the duck and goose farmer, loves doughnuts and goose livers. Get the group to go on a scavenger hunt for the supplies to make doughnut filled goose liver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campfire Chicken &amp; Dumplings</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/campfire-chicken-dumplings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 20:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/campfire-chicken-dumplings/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Campfire chicken &amp;amp; dumplings&amp;rsquo; is a great outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of campfire chicken &amp;amp; dumplings is to create Boggis&amp;rsquo;s favourite meal. This allows children to better understand nature and their environment and to embrace the story.
Resources  Fire Kit  /Dutch Oven/Knife/Ladle/Spoon/Fork Pot/Mixing Bowl 3 lbs. chicken thighs - cubed 1 tbs. vegetable oil 2 tbs. butter 1 medium yellow onion - finely diced 2/3 cups carrots - finely diced 2/3 cups celery - finely diced 1 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reshaping the Elf City</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/reshaping-the-elf-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 17:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/reshaping-the-elf-city/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Reshaping the elf city&amp;rsquo; is an activity where you need to get stuck in and start building. The aim of reshaping the elf city is to combine natural materials with imagination and creativity. This allows children to better understand nature and their environment and to embrace the story.
Resources  Natural materials from Forest Supply Store    Explanation To continue the elf story, explain that the area you are now looking at was once the elf city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find the Elf City</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/find-the-elf-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 17:39:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/find-the-elf-city/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Find the elf city&amp;rsquo; is a lovely outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of find the elf city is to join the first two activities to the next in a fluid manor. This allows them to explore their imaginative side and create the world that the elves live in.
Explanation Before setting off, you are given the directions to the secret city of the elves. It reads; friends of elf city you must use this guide to get safely through the dragon infested woodland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest Supply Store</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/forest-supply-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 17:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/forest-supply-store/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Forest supply store&amp;rsquo; is a great challenge that focuses on mathematics, teamwork, and planning skills. The aim of the forest supply store is to combine maths and their resources to create enough natural materials to help reshape the elf city. This allows children to practise their maths skills within a woodland settling.
Resources  Roll of String/Scissors Sticks/Leaves/Grass Stone/Rock/Cones/Nuts Palettes or man-made wood  Explanation Using the organic materials around your area, provide the group with a forest supply store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragon!</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 17:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/dragon/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Dragon!&amp;rsquo; be careful not to get caught by the dragon, so you need to be alert! The aim of dragon is to combine natural materials and the imagination to help keep the story alive. This allows children to keep focused on the leader within the woodland and to embrace the story.
Explanation Look for loose natural materials such as leaves, sticks, grasses, pine cones etc. Find a patch of grass and make your dragon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shoe Relay</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-shoe-relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-shoe-relay/</guid>
      <description>A great activity if you are needing to work on your shoe tying skills. The aim of the shoe relay is to combine speed and precision, to hopefully be the other team. This allows children to better understand team work, cooperation, strategy and express their shoe lace skills.
Resources  Shoes  Explanation The group is split into equal teams and lined up (sitting) behind the start line. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough for two team then just have one line and try and get them to bet their own time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giants, Dwarves &amp; Wizards</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/giants-dwarves-wizards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/giants-dwarves-wizards/</guid>
      <description>Have you heard of the classic game of &amp;lsquo;rock, paper, scissors&amp;rsquo;? &amp;lsquo;Giants, dwarves and wizards&amp;rsquo; is an activity that is virtually the same to play. Giants, dwarves and wizards to combine strategy and fare, to out wit the other team. This allows children to better understand team work, cooperation, strategy and express their creativity fare.
Explanation This is a slight twist on the ‘Rock, Paper, Scissors’. Go through the actions and make up a sound for each characters, which are;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helium Stick</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/helium-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/helium-stick/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Helium stick&amp;rsquo; is a challenging outdoor/indoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of helium stick is to work with others to pick up the stick, sounds easy, but not. This allows children to better understand team work, cooperation, and express their creativity.
Resources  A Long Stick Bangles or Washers  Explanation Group size: Ask the group to divide into two rows and stand opposite each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skyscraper</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/skyscraper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/skyscraper/</guid>
      <description>Can you make the tallest and strongest skyscraper? The aim of skyscraper is to work with others to create the biggest structure that can hold certain weights. This allows children to better understand team work, cooperation, and express their creativity.
Resources  Golf Ball Straws Paper Clips Scissors Tape Newspaper  Explanation Split group into teams, explaining about ‘Skyscrapers’ and that structures are getting bigger and heavier. The structure will be tall and hold a weight at the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Egg Challenge</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-egg-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-egg-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;The egg challenge&amp;rsquo; focuses on a team to create, discuss, and produce a vessel for an egg. The aim of the egg challenge is to create a pod that the egg goes in to help soften the impact once dropped at certain heights. This allows children to better understand their engineering skills, how to work best with others, and time pressure.
Resources  Eggs Natural Resources (Sticks, Grass, Leaves etc…) Scissors Tape String Newspaper  Explanation Split into teams and give them the challenge that they have to save ‘Humpty’ (the egg) from ‘THE GREAT FALL’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would you Rather?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/would-you-rather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/would-you-rather/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Would you rather?&amp;rsquo; is a great outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of would you rather is to decide which option you would prefer. This allows children to better understand themselves of what they truly would like.
Resources  A Rope Trivia Questions—Adapt questions to suit either the topic/ability/setting  Explanation Lay the rope out on the ground in a straight line. Ask the group to straddle the rope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spider &amp; Flies</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/spider-flies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/spider-flies/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Spider &amp;amp; Flies&amp;rsquo; is a version of the classic bulldog game. The aim of spider &amp;amp; flies is to combine speed and mobility to not get caught. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express their love for wide games.
Explanation This is a tame version of the classic bulldog game. One person is the spider and everyone else are known as flies, who stand at a base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth, Air or Water</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/earth-air-or-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/earth-air-or-water/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Earth, air or water&amp;rsquo; is a quick thinking outdoor/indoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of earth, air, water is to combine hand eye coordination and quick thinking. This allows children to work on their thinking skills and reactions.
Resources  A Ball or Pine cone  Explanation Ask everyone to stand in a circle. Throw a ball or a pine cone to a member of the group and say either ‘Earth’, ‘Air’ or ‘Water’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragons Breath</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/dragons-breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/dragons-breath/</guid>
      <description>This friendship bracelet activity can be used as part of a story where the wool is &amp;lsquo;dragons breath&amp;rsquo; and you need it to create a bracelet to keep you safe. The aim of dragons breath is to combine wool, teamwork and to create a unique bracelet. This allows children to better understand how to cooperate, work on their motor skills and express their imagination.
Resources  Wool (two different colours) Scissors Tape  Explanation Cut the wool and go to a tree or shrub and place all over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here, There, Where</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/here-there-where/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/here-there-where/</guid>
      <description>If you feel that your group just are not focuses, and you want to concentrate on their listening skills then this activity is great. The aim of here, there, where is to focus on concentrating to the three words. This allows children to focus on their listening skills, concentration skills, and better understand how to dismiss any distractions.
Resources  Three Big Circles (using rope or sticks) Open Space ( e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foil Parcels</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/foil-parcels/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/foil-parcels/</guid>
      <description>If you have good chopping skills or want to develop them, then this activity is for you. The aim of making foil parcels is to prepare, create, and cook apples over an open fire. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and develop a foundation of wild culinary skills.
Resources  Foil/Bowl/Knife/Chopping Board Zip Lock Bags Cooking Oil/Salt and Pepper/Veg Stock Cube/Range of Vegetables or Fruit Herbs (Optional) Table Spoon (tbsp) Fire Kit  /Water/Gloves/Bucket  Explanation Place one square of foil on top of another one and brush the top one with oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Apples</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/baked-apples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/baked-apples/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Baked apples&amp;rsquo; is a juicy outdoor activity suitable for any age. The aim of making baked apples is to prepare, create, and cook apples over an open fire. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and develop a foundation of wild culinary skills.
Resources  Foil Apple/Sultanas/Brown Sugar Cinnamon Apple Corer or Knife Tea Spoon (TSP) Fire Kit  /Water/Gloves/Bucket  Explanation Core the apple then put it in the middle of a square of tinfoil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bannock</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/bannock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/bannock/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever made bread? The aim of making bannock bread is to prepare, create, and cook bread over an open fire. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and develop a foundation of wild culinary skills.
Resources  Plastic Food Bags (Zip Lock) A Cup Chopping Board Tea Spoon (TSP) Table Spoon (TBSP) Flour/Baking Powder/Salt/Powdered Milk/Oil or Butter/Herbs Fire Kit/Water/Gloves/Bucket  Explanation Put all of these ingredients into a zip lock plastic bag; 1 cup of flour, 1 level tsp baking powder, 1/4 tsp salt, 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Bananas</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/chocolate-bananas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/chocolate-bananas/</guid>
      <description>Combining chocolate, bananas, and fire is always a good concoction that makes a great activity. The aim of making chocolate bananas is to show fruit in a different light, and how fire can help create tasty delights. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and develop a foundation of culinary skills.
Resources  Chopping Board/Knife Cooking Pot/Bowls/Spoons Banana/Chocolate Buttons/Mini Marsh Mellows Foil Bin Bag Grill (if you have one) Fire Kit  /Water/Gloves/Bucket  Explanation Take a square of foil, then put your banana in the centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nettle Soup</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/nettle-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/nettle-soup/</guid>
      <description>Nettles have always been looked at as a weed that can sting you, so to make it into soup sounds crazy. Making nettle soup is to show that you can forage and cook your our meal in the woodland. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and develop a foundation of culinary skills.
Resources  Chopping Board/Knife Cooking Pots/Sieve/Bowls/Spoons Bag/Deep Tray Scissors Fire Kit  /Water/Gloves/Bucket Oil A Bag of Nettles A Large Onion, Diced 3 Potatoes, Diced 4 Celery Sticks, Diced 2 Garlic Cloves, Diced 2 Veg Stock Cubes Almond Milk  Explanation Collect a bag of nettle tops (just the first 4-6 leaves) in your carrier bag or tray using the scissors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Dyes</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-dyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-dyes/</guid>
      <description>This activity combines natural materials to produce unique stained fabrics. This allows children to better understand natural dyes, their effects and their properties.
Resources  Blackberries, salt, water and vinegar. Cooking pot and cup (more pots if you want to have more colours). Material (e.g. canvas). String or elastic bands. Small stones. Fire kit  : water, gloves and a bucket.  Explanation Mash up the blackberries in a large cooking pot (1 cup of salt to 2 cups of berries to 8 cups of water).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic Flame Pine Cones</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/magic-flame-pine-cones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/magic-flame-pine-cones/</guid>
      <description>A camp fire is a magical resource, especially if, when burning, different colours emerged from it. The aim of magic flame pine cones is to enhance story telling by creating mesmerising flames using different chemicals. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and the science behind these fantastic flames.
Resources  Salt/potassium chloride/borax Bowl Water Newspaper Fire kit  /water/gloves/bucket Objects (weigh down pine cones)  Explanation Making Magic Flamed Pine Cones Preparing your Pine Cones Get a large bowl of water, put your pine cones in, and add in as much salt as the water will take.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cup of Tea</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/cup-of-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/cup-of-tea/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Cup of tea&amp;rsquo; is a refreshing outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of making a cup of tea is to look at producing a refreshment with fire whilst out in the woods. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and the use of fire.
Resources  Fire kit  /water/gloves/bucket Kelly Kettle (if trained) Tea bags/water/milk/sugar Mugs Spoons Grill (if have one) Billy can/pot  Explanation The challenge is all about planning ahead, a simple activity used everyday in the urban environment could be looked at as a complex activity within the woodland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Been Drawing</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/youve-been-drawing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/youve-been-drawing/</guid>
      <description>What an opportunity for anyone to use charcoal as a pencil in creating something artistic. The aim of you&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing is to encourage our art skills and the ability to express what we want on natural materials, canvas or paper. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and the power of expression.
Resources  Fire Kit/Water/Gloves/Bucket Charcoal (Ash Pencils) Paper, Card, or Canvas  Explanation After having a fire use the charcoal to create observational drawings or a favourite memory of the day (make sure the charcoal is safe to touch).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire/Words/Mobile</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/fire-words-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/fire-words-mobile/</guid>
      <description>The natural television (fire) is a great way of teasing words out of your mind. &amp;lsquo;Fire/words/mobiles&amp;rsquo; aims to encourage us to think of words that can describe fire. This allows children to better understand nature and their environment and enhance there word collection.
Resources  Fire Kit  /Water/Gloves/Bucket Coloured Cards (Red, Yellow &amp;amp; Orange) Hole Puncher String Scissors Charcoal  Explanation When the group are sitting around the fire looking at the flames, ask them what they can see, think of adjectives about the fire (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stick Totem Poles</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/stick-totem-poles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/stick-totem-poles/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Stick totem poles&amp;rsquo; is a fulfilling outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of making a stick totem pole is to try and understand the native Americans point of view. This also allows children to better understand different cultures, nature, their environments and to express creativity.
Resources  Clay Stick  Explanation This idea has been taken from the native American totem poles carved with animals, plants, humans and mythical creatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Masks</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-masks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-masks/</guid>
      <description>Become one of the creatures that live within the woodland by creating a wild mask. Immerse yourself into nature and use your skills to produced this great creation (mask), which will aid you in falling deeper into your fantastic imagination. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources  String Scissors Tape/Double Sided Tape Cardboard Ruler/Pencil  Explanation Wild Masks To hold an eye mask in place, tape a straight stick on the back at one side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Woody Crown</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-woody-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-woody-crown/</guid>
      <description>Creating a woody crown will provide a doorway for you and your group into the world of royalty. The aim of making this crown is to focus on fine motor skills and a story about kings and queens. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources  Green Willow/Reactive or New Growth Ivy/Clematis Stem/Sticky Tape/Raffia Glue/Fabric/Card/Scissors  Explanation What can you find to decorate a crown fit for a woodland fairy or forest king/queen?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Been Framed</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/youve-been-framed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/youve-been-framed/</guid>
      <description>This tangible outdoor activity shows you how to create a memorable creation. The aim of you&amp;rsquo;ve been framed is to create a frame using thick sticks found in the woodland. This allows children to better understand knot tying, nature and their environment.
Resources  Vines/String Secateurs/Scissors  Explanation You could either make a frame or get the group to find a decayed log or stick with a hole in it (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy/Fish Sticks</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/fairy-fish-sticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/fairy-fish-sticks/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Fairy/fish sticks&amp;rsquo; is a magical outdoor activity that looks at taking you on great adventures. This allows children to better understand how to tie knots, nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources  Willow/Ivy Coloured Fabric/Felting Wool Wool Scissors  Explanation Weave green willow into fish or fairies, adding more willow or creeper stems to decorate.
Wrap brightly coloured fabric or felting wool round a bendy stick. Wind knitting wool over the top to secure it in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Hobby Animals</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-hobby-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-hobby-animals/</guid>
      <description>Hobby animals are great fun to create, as they can become part of your story and even be the star of the show. The focus of making a hobby animal is to immerse yourself into a magical world and produce a great creature. This allows children to better understand their craft skills, nature and their environment.
Resources  Sock/s Newspaper/Straw String Double Sided Tape Buttons/Wool/Natural Materials  Explanation Stuff a sock with scrunched-up newspaper or straw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Stick &amp; Clay Animals</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-stick-clay-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-stick-clay-animals/</guid>
      <description>The woodland is alive with small creatures, could you creative them using sticks or clay? Making stick and clay animals focuses on fine motor skills and imagination. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources  Clay Paints String Paper/Pencil Scissors  Explanation Mould clay into the shape of an animal, an imaginary monster or even Rudolf the red-nosed reindeer. Use sticks and twigs, and other natural materials to add legs, antlers or horns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Broom</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-broom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-broom/</guid>
      <description>Young children of all abilities can imagine they are fly in and out of great mystical stories. Immerse yourself into a magical world and try to produce a great creation. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources  String/Bramble Runners Clematis Stems/New Tree Growth/Sticks Scissors  Explanation Choose a sturdy stick. If you plan to fly long distances, make sure it is strong and has a comfy place to sit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Scavenging Stick</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-scavenging-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-scavenging-stick/</guid>
      <description>This great outdoor activity can send you on a journey, provide many new experiences. The aim of making a scavenging stick is to show yourself and others that you have been on a memorable walk. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express story telling skills.
Resources  Coloured Wool/Elastic Bands Double Sided Tape Paints/Paint Brushes Scissors  Explanation A Story Stick Attach loose natural materials to a special stick with coloured wools, elastic bands or double sided tape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Star</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-star/</guid>
      <description>Can you make a square or triangle out of natural material? Making a star is a great challenging maths creation that can be done indoors or out. The aim of it is to combine natural materials to produce a unique shape. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express an interest in shapes.
Resources  Sticks Secateurs Scissors String Double Sided Tape (optional) Willow (optional)  Explanation Have 5 sticks equal sizes, and attach 1st and 2nd stick together with string (either a shear lashing  or use a knot/lashing/hitch).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grass Dolls</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/grass-dolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/grass-dolls/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Grass dolls&amp;rsquo; is a tactile outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of grass dolls is to create one or many little dolls that work on your motor skills, knot skills, and imagination. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources  Wool/Thread Scissors  Explanation Hold a clump of long grass in your hand, binding them together roughly in the middle, this will be the doll’s body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Sculptures</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-sculptures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-sculptures/</guid>
      <description>To be able to go into a woodland and simple create a wild sculpture is a great way of expressing yourself. The aim of this activity is to combine natural materials to produce a unique piece of art. This allows children to better understand nature, the environment and how to express their creative side.
Explanation Wild Sculptures Look for loose natural materials such as leaves, sticks, grasses, pine cones etc. Find a patch of grass and make a character like the Gruffalo or make a collage of a bird, a dragon, a monster or whatever inspires you when you look at the natural materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hedgehog Home</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hedgehog-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hedgehog-home/</guid>
      <description>Help the hedgehog! We need to be more aware at providing homes for hedgehogs. The aim of this thoughtful activity is building a hedgehog home, which shows individuals how they can make a difference and provide homes for the little creatures. This allows children to have a better understand of nature and how to express their love for animals.
Resources  Bricks Plastic Box/Lid Newspaper/Straw  Explanation Choose a quiet spot that won’t be disturbed, maybe near a fence or hedge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaf Prints</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/leaf-prints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/leaf-prints/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to use the leaves within the woodland to make great pieces of art? &amp;lsquo;Leaf prints&amp;rsquo; use leaves as a resource to make natural art allowing children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources  Strong Paper/Card/Material/Fabric/Plate/Dish Paints/Inks Brushes/Rollers Water  Explanation Try to find interesting leaves, either dip in, brush or roller on paint then press down onto paper, card, fabric or material (wood).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Storyboards</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-storyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-storyboards/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever made a storyboard? This activity helps use tell great stories in a unique way. The aim of wild storyboards is to combine natural materials to produce a story allowing others to guess what it is. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity and imagination.
Explanation Split into two or more groups, then each group thinks of a well known story e.g. Jack and the Beanstalk, The Bear Hunt, Stickman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic Carpets/Flying Creatures</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/magic-carpets-flying-creatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/magic-carpets-flying-creatures/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Magic carpets/flying creatures&amp;rsquo; are fun-loving outdoor activities that aim to combine your designing skills with your imagination. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity and imagination.
Explanation Woodland Magic Carpets In a woodland clearing (open space), use sticks to make a frame. Fill the frame with a pattern or picture made from coloured leaves, seeds, berries and sticks. You could also make smaller frames, so that each person can design their own section of the carpet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Woodland Monsters</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-woodland-monsters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-woodland-monsters/</guid>
      <description>Within the woodland young children of all abilities are making their own woodland monsters. The aim of making these woodland monsters is to combine your imagination, creativity, and use natural materials to produce weird and wonderful woodland creatures. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity and imagination.
Resources  Clay  Explanation Look for interesting shapes in tree trunks, branches, tree stumps or fallen logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New World</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/new-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/new-world/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;New world&amp;rsquo; is a playful outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of new world is to help your toys by creating a place for them to play. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity and imagination.
Resources  Toy Soldiers Farm Animals  Explanation Find a space close by and create a miniature world in which the toys are the only non-natural things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elf House</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/elf-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/elf-house/</guid>
      <description>Suitable for young children of all abilities, &amp;rsquo;elf house&amp;rsquo; is a delightful outdoor activity, which aim&amp;rsquo;s to make either a home for an elf or help to build a village for all elves. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and express creativity and imagination.
Explanation Firstly find a good spot to start the build. This could be among tree roots, in hollow stumps, within a pile of stones, or in a dip in the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Stick Characters</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-stick-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-stick-characters/</guid>
      <description>This hands on outdoor activity, aim&amp;rsquo;s to make stick characters by combining natural materials to produce unique characters from clay. These character could have a role within a story or small play. This allows children to better understand nature, the environment and to express their creativity and imagination.
Resources  Clay Masking Tape  Explanation Look for the most twisted, gnarled stick you can find. Could it become a little man, a scary troll or a magical sprite?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavenger Hunt</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/scavenger-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/scavenger-hunt/</guid>
      <description>Hunting for different objects is a joyous outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of a scavenger hunt is to collect natural materials, which are based around the senses. This allows children to better understand nature, the environment and develop their explorative skills.
Resources  Bag  Explanation The scavenger hunt can be run by asking the group to pick up specific items e.g. find 3 different leaves or find a smooth stick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust Walk</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/trust-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/trust-walk/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Trust walk&amp;rsquo; is a fun-loving outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of a trust walk is to combine natural materials to create a unique route in the mind. This allows children to better understand their senses and develop a good foundation of trust in others.
Resources  Blindfolds  Explanation Partner up and choose who will be blindfolded first. The guide will then take the blindfolded group member around the area and make sure that they stop and feel features like shrubs and trees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is it?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/what-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/what-is-it/</guid>
      <description>This activity is a classic game that is played by all, suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of what is it, is to blend natural materials together to produce a unique sensory activity. This allows children to better understand natural objects and intensify their senses.
Resources  Draw String Bag Range of Natural Objects  Explanation Collecting a range of natural objects like; a pine cone, a twig, a conker, a feather, a leaf, some mosh, a snail shell, or a stone, and putting them into a draw string bag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hand Scents</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hand-scents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hand-scents/</guid>
      <description>Suitable for young children of all abilities, this great icebreaker will help you to smell a range of different scents and interact with each other, within the group. The aim of hand scents is to combine unique aromas with others within your group. This allows children to better understand their group and how to distinguish between different scents.
Resources  Cloth Squares Perfumes/Oils  Explanation Using different perfumes, put a dab on each person’s hand or on a small square of cloth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Postcards</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/sound-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/sound-postcards/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Sound postcards&amp;rsquo; is a calming and thoughtful outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of sound postcards is to focus the mind and listen out for sounds around the area. This allows children to better understand nature, the environment, and to express their ability to sit and listen.
Resources  Postcards Pencils  Explanation Show the group how to pull an imaginary veil over their heads. This is a veil of silence and when they are wearing it, they must not speak or make a sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blindfold Shapes</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/blindfold-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/blindfold-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Can you make shapes using a rope? This team related outdoor activity will push your communication teamwork skills. The aim of blindfold shapes is to focus only on the ability to listen to others and feel where the group want to go due to the connection of the team when creating a shape. This allows children to better understand each other and also have empathy with others who have lost their sight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mud Pit</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/mud-pit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/mud-pit/</guid>
      <description>Get messy in this fun outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of a mud pit is to combine natural materials to produce a unique play area. This allows children the freedom to use their imagination, creativity, and senses within the natural world.
Resources  Water Bucket Toys (cars/soldiers/animals)  Explanation Make a mud pit by pouring a lot of water on a soiled area or wait until a storm has been.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop &amp; Listen</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/stop-listen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/stop-listen/</guid>
      <description>This activity will help you unwind as you will be focusing on sounds around you. The aim of stop and listen is to focus your mind on particular natural sounds. This allows children to have a better appreciation of the natural world.
Explanation Unless we make time to listen to the sounds, many of them will be lost into the background. If you listen carefully, you might be able to hear; the flapping of a swallow, the drumming of a woodpecker, the rustle of a breeze through the trees, the trickle of a stream, a falling leaf landing on the ground, or even the popping of seed cases in the sunshine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find your Tree</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/find-your-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/find-your-tree/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Find your tree&amp;rsquo; will give you the opportunity to focus on your senses. The aim of finding your tree is cooperation and trust with others to find your tree. This allows children to better understand their senses and develop a good foundation of trust in others.
Resources  Blindfolds  Explanation Divide the group into pairs or threes. One member of the group is blindfolded and are led by their peer/s to a tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smelly Cocktails</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/smelly-cocktails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/smelly-cocktails/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Smelly cocktails&amp;rsquo; is a playful outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of smelly cocktails is to combine natural materials to produce unique aromas. This allows children to better understand nature and the environment and to express their creativity.
Resources  Stick/Spoon Plastic Cup/Mug Natural Materials  Explanation Pour a little bit of water into a clear plastic cup and add fallen petals, natural herbs, leaves or wild fruits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool Guidance</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/tool-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/tool-guidance/</guid>
      <description>Nature-base sessions use a range of different types of tools and using these tools gives children the opportunity to develop new practical skills and build their confidence. The aim is to ensure that all group members using tools do so safely and with a reduced level of risk. The information below will make you aware of your present skill level and also the steps you need to take in order to improve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Risk Assessments</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/dynamic-risk-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/dynamic-risk-assessments/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Dynamic risk assessments&amp;rsquo; are processes carried out by the leader during the activity, to reduce risk towards the group. By analysing and assessing the environment, the leader can identify hazards and make on the spot decisions in regards to their own/group safety. The aim of this page is to make you aware of what you may need to look out for and what questions you need to ask yourself.
Download our Dynamic Risk Assessment  As a leader, you have the responsibility to give your group a quality experience, yet you equally have the responsibility to make sure they are safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic Risk Assessments</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/generic-risk-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/generic-risk-assessments/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Generic risk assessments&amp;rsquo; (GRAs) let the reader know the risks to be aware of and how to reduce them whilst performing a particular activity. GRAs are risk assessments, which contain information of the conditions and hazards for that particular activity.
Before carrying out an activity, two assessments will have had to be made, one for the site (site risk assessment  - SRA), and another for the particular activity (GRA). The GRA has to be used in conjunction with the SRA form, and could potentially have the same actual risks recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Risk Assessments</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/site-risk-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/site-risk-assessments/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Site risk assessments&amp;rsquo; (SRAs) also known as &amp;lsquo;site specific risk assessments&amp;rsquo; inform the reader of actual risks and how to reduce them. SRAs are risk assessments, which contain information of the conditions and hazards for that particular site.
Before carrying out an activity, two assessments will have had to be made, one for the site (SRA), and another for the particular activity (generic risk assessment  - GRA). The SRA has to be used in conjunction with the GRA form, and could potentially have the same actual risks recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session Structure</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/session-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/session-structure/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Session Structure&amp;rsquo; is a good way in making sure you have covered all you need to, before, within, and after the activity. The aim of this list is to help keep you on task, so that you do not miss anything that will hinder the quality or safety of the session. Within these lists you might have to click on to the links to explore more of what you need to bear in mind when taking a group outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Session Standards</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/general-session-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/general-session-standards/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;General session standards&amp;rsquo; are not essential but are a good way in making sure you stick to good practise. These standards that leaders should adhere to have been set down by Adventurous Activities Licencing Authority (AALA)  , and will ensure that a good level of risk management is achieved.
Leader’s responsibilities Prior to the activity the leader is responsible for:  Booking the facility (area that will be used for the activity) Conducting a routine visual and physical check of the equipment to be used Ensuring first aid equipment is available throughout the session Updating an on site/generic risk assessment if needed Collecting the group (conducting the signing out procedure if taking group off site) Signing out medication of individual pupils (if necessary)  During the session the leader is responsible for:  Setting out the aims of the session Running the session with a suitable level of challenge Group management during the activity Personal development  On completion of the session the leader is responsible for:  Feedback/review to group (through talking, pictures, ‘thumbs up/thumbs down’) Checking equipment for damage/recording use/completing logs as required Reporting accidents/near misses Collecting and returning the equipment Leaving the site/facility in a clean and safe condition  Sessions are physically and mentally demanding as well as incredibly fulfilling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire Area Checklist</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/fire-area-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/fire-area-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Fire area checklist&amp;rsquo; is very important as it guides you through stages of making, using and decommissioning a fire, and also how the group should act around it.
Before making a fire Have you checked;  All your safety equipment (e.g. first aid kit including burns kit, mobile phone) The fire box (e.g. gauntlets, fire steel, cotton wool, fire blanket) If you have a bucket of water The weather (thunder, lighting, and wind)  The above information is also relevant for kettles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire Guidance</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/fire-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/fire-guidance/</guid>
      <description>Nature-base sessions use fire as a great tool to give children the opportunity to develop new practical skills and build their confidence. The aim is to ensure that all group members using fire within an activity do so safely and with a reduced level of risk. The information below will make you aware of your present skill level and also the steps you need to take in order to improve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rehoming Creatures</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/rehoming-creatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/rehoming-creatures/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Rehoming creatures&amp;rsquo; is a focused group of activities that priorities on firstly finding out who needs helping and then focusing our efforts in building the homes. If you are looking for unique ways to engage yourself and other surrounding data collection then this section is where you should start.
These activities develop your; trust, cooperation, patience, teamwork, life skills, addition, estimating, and record taking. Each activity will ooze so many other benefits, so why not get choosing and try them out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to The Fantastic Mr Fox</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-introduction-to-the-fantastic-mr-fox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-introduction-to-the-fantastic-mr-fox/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;An introduction to The Fantastic Mr Fox&amp;rsquo; is a section of themed activities that focuses on the famous story about a fox and his family, trying to outwit a bunch of farmers to survive. If you are looking for story based maths-focused activities then this section is where you should start.
The selection of activities are there to help develop; your trust, leadership, cooperation, patience, teamwork, life skills, and use and apply the maths knowledge within life tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction of The Elf Story</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-introduction-of-the-elf-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-introduction-of-the-elf-story/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;An introduction to the elf story&amp;rsquo; is a section of themed activities that focuses on a secret story about helping restore the elves city  , which has been destroyed by the dragon. If you are looking for story based maths-focused activities then this section is where you should start. The selection of activities are there to help develop your; trust, leadership, cooperation, patience, teamwork, life skills, and use and apply the maths knowledge within life tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moss Graffiti: Dare to Try?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mossgraffitidaretotry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mossgraffitidaretotry/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to create art with natural materials? Moss art or moss graffiti is a safe, interactive and enjoyable activity for families, schools and groups. This guide will show you different ways of using moss to have fun and reconnect with nature.
What we cover in this guide:
 the origins of ‘moss graffiti’ the development of moss graffiti, as an art form different types of moss graffiti; and how easy it is to get into creating art with moss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mark to Guide Schools Towards a Better Future</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/a-mark-to-guide-schools-towards-a-better-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/a-mark-to-guide-schools-towards-a-better-future/</guid>
      <description>Are schools ready to move towards a more interesting and engaging curriculum? This article talks about how schools can gain a particular accreditation (at numerous levels) that helps transform how pupils learn, giving them a more valuable school experience.
In 2006, the government released the Learning Outside the Classroom (LOtC) Manifesto  , explaining their vision to provide children with approaches to experiential learning as the main focus. Since then the Council of Learning Outside the Classroom (CLOtC) developed and supported schools going for their LOtC Mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Outside and Play</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/get-outside-and-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 23:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/get-outside-and-play/</guid>
      <description>Play is a natural behaviour, instinctively creating imaginative stories, games, and activities, which help develop social, emotional, intellectual, and physical skills. This creative language can help children integrate themselves with each other and understand the world around them.
In this article &amp;lsquo;get outside and play&amp;rsquo; is defined as a way to naturally learn and develop their soft skills by experiencing nature in its true form. This is important because not all children are accessing outdoor play and not all children learn best in the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are School Playtime&#39;s as Good as They Could be?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/are-school-playtimes-as-good-as-they-could-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/are-school-playtimes-as-good-as-they-could-be/</guid>
      <description>Schools have an enormous responsibility in making sure children progress, yet loosely supervised, unstructured free play known as &amp;lsquo;playtime&amp;rsquo; is not unfortunately what is focused upon. This is not their fault, as the pressure for progressive stats on school children has become a priority. This article gives schools the opportunity to gain advise in changing the way we manage &amp;lsquo;playtime&amp;rsquo; for the better.
Outdoor Play and Learning (OPAL) was founded by Michael Follett (Director of OPAL), who&amp;rsquo;s primary programme has helped hundreds of schools and early learning centres create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Environmental Award that Benefits Young People and Families</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-environmental-award-that-benefits-young-people-and-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-environmental-award-that-benefits-young-people-and-families/</guid>
      <description>Have you wanted to take your child/class out to explore the natural world, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know how? This article highlights an award that gives structure and support to discover the outdoors.
In 1997, the John Muir Trust (the leading wild land conservation charity in the UK) created an environmental award scheme to encourage people of all backgrounds to connect with, enjoy, and care for wild places.
Origins of the John Muir Award John Muir Trust takes its name and inspiration from John Muir (1838-1914), the pioneering, influential Scots-born American conservationist, who was passionate about the wild.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Hidden Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/unlocking-the-hidden-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 15:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/unlocking-the-hidden-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>The hidden curriculum considers what the pupil is learning as a side effect of the schooling process. The skill can be both positive or negative and is affected by social values, which a teacher holds and operates by. The article will look at whether the outdoors can help unlock the features of the hidden curriculum.
Michelle Sager (thought to be a pioneer in this field) has looked at understanding the hidden curriculum by connecting teachers to themselves, their students, and the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residential Trips are Essential for Children&#39;s Development</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/residential-trips-are-essential-for-childrens-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 23:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/residential-trips-are-essential-for-childrens-development/</guid>
      <description>In this article it will explain about an initiative that has shown overwhelming statics, towards the positive impacts to why it is important for children to go away on school trips.
In 2009, Paul Hamlyn Foundation invited a number of primary, secondary and special schools across the UK to work with &amp;lsquo;Learning Away&amp;rsquo; to develop and pilot original residential learning programmes. A residential trip is understood by schools and education establishments as an overnight trip.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
