<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tool and Fire Guidance on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tool and Fire Guidance on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guide to using a Kettle</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/guide-to-using-a-kettle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 23:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/guide-to-using-a-kettle/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Guide to using a kettle&amp;rsquo; is an important skill to learn and will ensure the you use your kettle safely.
The Ghillie kettle and the Kelly kettle are very similar products. There are some slight differences but they achieve the same goal, which is to boil water. The Ghillie Kettle  is made in the UK, whereas the Kelly Kettle  is made in America.
Clearing your area Make sure you have a clear surface when preparing your fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide to Fire Making</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/guide-to-fire-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 23:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/guide-to-fire-making/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Guide to fire making&amp;rsquo; is a great skill to learn, as it will help you achieve a number of activities. This guide is to help you make and manage your fire safely. Also by creating and managing your fire with good practise, you are showing your group how it is supposed to be performed safely.
Clearing your area Make sure you have a clear surface when preparing your fire. This reduces the risk of setting fire to other parts of a woodland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool Guidance</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/tool-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/tool-guidance/</guid>
      <description>Nature-base sessions use a range of different types of tools and using these tools gives children the opportunity to develop new practical skills and build their confidence. The aim is to ensure that all group members using tools do so safely and with a reduced level of risk. The information below will make you aware of your present skill level and also the steps you need to take in order to improve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire Area Checklist</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/fire-area-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/fire-area-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Fire area checklist&amp;rsquo; is very important as it guides you through stages of making, using and decommissioning a fire, and also how the group should act around it.
Before making a fire Have you checked;  All your safety equipment (e.g. first aid kit including burns kit, mobile phone) The fire box (e.g. gauntlets, fire steel, cotton wool, fire blanket) If you have a bucket of water The weather (thunder, lighting, and wind)  The above information is also relevant for kettles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire Guidance</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/fire-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/tool-and-fire-guidance/fire-guidance/</guid>
      <description>Nature-base sessions use fire as a great tool to give children the opportunity to develop new practical skills and build their confidence. The aim is to ensure that all group members using fire within an activity do so safely and with a reduced level of risk. The information below will make you aware of your present skill level and also the steps you need to take in order to improve.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
