<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research/Statistics on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/research/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research/Statistics on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/research/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This Preventable Disorder is Destroying our Children&#39;s Future</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/this-preventable-disorder-is-destroying-our-childrens-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/this-preventable-disorder-is-destroying-our-childrens-future/</guid>
      <description>Are less children experiencing outdoor environments? This article talks about why children don&amp;rsquo;t play outside in today&amp;rsquo;s society and due to this could be labelled with having &amp;rsquo;nature deficit disorder&amp;rsquo; (NDD).
NDD was coined by Richard Louv (American author) in his book, &amp;lsquo;Last Child in the Woods&amp;rsquo;  to highlight the problem he sees for young children today, and for their level of experience within natural environments, locally or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Outdoor Learning in Schools be Compulsory?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/should-outdoor-learning-in-schools-be-compulsory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/should-outdoor-learning-in-schools-be-compulsory/</guid>
      <description>If you had to choose between an education that offered your children an enjoyable learning experience that improved their social skills and made them generally happier and healthier, or one that didn&amp;rsquo;t, which would you choose?
If, that same educational experience were to improve the health and well-being of the teachers teaching your child, improve their job satisfaction and had a positive impact on their teaching practice, would you make that educational experience compulsory?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Learning Explained</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</guid>
      <description>For many years people have enjoyed embracing the natural environment. Playing in fields until tea time was the norm. Nowadays, our society doesn&amp;rsquo;t engage with nature as it used too. There have been companies, through the years, delivering outdoor experiences, but is this enough?
In this article, we will look at how new evidence and practises have altered society&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the importance of the outdoors. How the term outdoor learning, has been coined, and why our society should be embracing the outdoors on a wide scale, within their daily lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residential Trips are Essential for Children&#39;s Development</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/residential-trips-are-essential-for-childrens-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 23:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/residential-trips-are-essential-for-childrens-development/</guid>
      <description>In this article it will explain about an initiative that has shown overwhelming statics, towards the positive impacts to why it is important for children to go away on school trips.
In 2009, Paul Hamlyn Foundation invited a number of primary, secondary and special schools across the UK to work with &amp;lsquo;Learning Away&amp;rsquo; to develop and pilot original residential learning programmes. A residential trip is understood by schools and education establishments as an overnight trip.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
