<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Craft on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/craft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Craft on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:31:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/craft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stick Totem Poles</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/stick-totem-poles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/stick-totem-poles/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Stick totem poles&amp;rsquo; is a fulfilling outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of making a stick totem pole is to try and understand the native Americans point of view. This also allows children to better understand different cultures, nature, their environments and to express creativity.
Resources Clay Stick Explanation This idea has been taken from the native American totem poles carved with animals, plants, humans and mythical creatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Masks</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-masks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-masks/</guid>
      <description>Become one of the creatures that live within the woodland by creating a wild mask. Immerse yourself into nature and use your skills to produced this great creation (mask), which will aid you in falling deeper into your fantastic imagination. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources String Scissors Tape/Double Sided Tape Cardboard Ruler/Pencil Explanation Wild Masks To hold an eye mask in place, tape a straight stick on the back at one side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Woody Crown</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-woody-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-woody-crown/</guid>
      <description>Creating a woody crown will provide a doorway for you and your group into the world of royalty. The aim of making this crown is to focus on fine motor skills and a story about kings and queens. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources Green Willow/Reactive or New Growth Ivy/Clematis Stem/Sticky Tape/Raffia Glue/Fabric/Card/Scissors Explanation What can you find to decorate a crown fit for a woodland fairy or forest king/queen?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Been Framed</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/youve-been-framed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/youve-been-framed/</guid>
      <description>This tangible outdoor activity shows you how to create a memorable creation. The aim of you&amp;rsquo;ve been framed is to create a frame using thick sticks found in the woodland. This allows children to better understand knot tying, nature and their environment.
Resources Vines/String Secateurs/Scissors Explanation You could either make a frame or get the group to find a decayed log or stick with a hole in it (e.g. using it like a telescope).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy/Fish Sticks</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/fairy-fish-sticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/fairy-fish-sticks/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Fairy/fish sticks&amp;rsquo; is a magical outdoor activity that looks at taking you on great adventures. This allows children to better understand how to tie knots, nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources Willow/Ivy Coloured Fabric/Felting Wool Wool Scissors Explanation Weave green willow into fish or fairies, adding more willow or creeper stems to decorate.
Wrap brightly coloured fabric or felting wool round a bendy stick. Wind knitting wool over the top to secure it in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Hobby Animals</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-hobby-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-hobby-animals/</guid>
      <description>Hobby animals are great fun to create, as they can become part of your story and even be the star of the show. The focus of making a hobby animal is to immerse yourself into a magical world and produce a great creature. This allows children to better understand their craft skills, nature and their environment.
Resources Sock/s Newspaper/Straw String Double Sided Tape Buttons/Wool/Natural Materials Explanation Stuff a sock with scrunched-up newspaper or straw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Stick &amp; Clay Animals</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-stick-clay-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-stick-clay-animals/</guid>
      <description>The woodland is alive with small creatures, could you creative them using sticks or clay? Making stick and clay animals focuses on fine motor skills and imagination. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources Clay Paints String Paper/Pencil Scissors Explanation Mould clay into the shape of an animal, an imaginary monster or even Rudolf the red-nosed reindeer. Use sticks and twigs, and other natural materials to add legs, antlers or horns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Broom</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-broom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-broom/</guid>
      <description>Young children of all abilities can imagine they are fly in and out of great mystical stories. Immerse yourself into a magical world and try to produce a great creation. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources String/Bramble Runners Clematis Stems/New Tree Growth/Sticks Scissors Explanation Choose a sturdy stick. If you plan to fly long distances, make sure it is strong and has a comfy place to sit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Scavenging Stick</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-scavenging-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-scavenging-stick/</guid>
      <description>This great outdoor activity can send you on a journey, provide many new experiences. The aim of making a scavenging stick is to show yourself and others that you have been on a memorable walk. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express story telling skills.
Resources Coloured Wool/Elastic Bands Double Sided Tape Paints/Paint Brushes Scissors Explanation A Story Stick Attach loose natural materials to a special stick with coloured wools, elastic bands or double sided tape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Star</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-star/</guid>
      <description>Can you make a square or triangle out of natural material? Making a star is a great challenging maths creation that can be done indoors or out. The aim of it is to combine natural materials to produce a unique shape. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express an interest in shapes.
Resources Sticks Secateurs Scissors String Double Sided Tape (optional) Willow (optional) Explanation Have 5 sticks equal sizes, and attach 1st and 2nd stick together with string (either a shear lashing or use a knot/lashing/hitch).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
