<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health and Safety Guidance on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health and Safety Guidance on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:21:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daily Risk Assessments</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/daily-risk-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 21:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/daily-risk-assessments/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Daily risk assessments&amp;rsquo; (DRAs) let the reader know of present hazards, which have either been dealt with or not. DRAs are active risk assessment forms, which need to be consulted and updated for new hazards on any particular site.
Download our Daily Risk Assessment Completing a DRA This form is for anyone who has noticed a hazard in and around the site. If you see a new hazard then write it down on the DRA form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Risk Assessments</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/dynamic-risk-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/dynamic-risk-assessments/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Dynamic risk assessments&amp;rsquo; are processes carried out by the leader during the activity, to reduce risk towards the group. By analysing and assessing the environment, the leader can identify hazards and make on the spot decisions in regards to their own/group safety. The aim of this page is to make you aware of what you may need to look out for and what questions you need to ask yourself.
Download our Dynamic Risk Assessment As a leader, you have the responsibility to give your group a quality experience, yet you equally have the responsibility to make sure they are safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic Risk Assessments</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/generic-risk-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/generic-risk-assessments/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Generic risk assessments&amp;rsquo; (GRAs) let the reader know the risks to be aware of and how to reduce them whilst performing a particular activity. GRAs are risk assessments, which contain information of the conditions and hazards for that particular activity.
Before carrying out an activity, two assessments will have had to be made, one for the site ( site risk assessment - SRA), and another for the particular activity (GRA). The GRA has to be used in conjunction with the SRA form, and could potentially have the same actual risks recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Risk Assessments</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/site-risk-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/health-and-safety-guidance/site-risk-assessments/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Site risk assessments&amp;rsquo; (SRAs) also known as &amp;lsquo;site specific risk assessments&amp;rsquo; inform the reader of actual risks and how to reduce them. SRAs are risk assessments, which contain information of the conditions and hazards for that particular site.
Before carrying out an activity, two assessments will have had to be made, one for the site (SRA), and another for the particular activity ( generic risk assessment - GRA). The SRA has to be used in conjunction with the GRA form, and could potentially have the same actual risks recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
