<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Handling on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/data-handling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Handling on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 23:09:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/data-handling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hungry Creatures</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hungry-creatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 23:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hungry-creatures/</guid>
      <description>Everyone gets hungry, even bugs, so why not try and help them with their food shop. The aim of hungry creatures is to work out how much food to give to the creatures within the area your looking. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and how to create a tally chart.
Resources Pencil/Ruler/Paper Explanation Get into pairs and find specific areas to conduct your search. Find different types of creatures and record them on a tally chart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leafy Leaves</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/leafy-leaves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 23:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/leafy-leaves/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Leafy leaves&amp;rsquo; is a great way of collecting all different types of leaves and really looking and understanding them. The aim of leafy leaves is to combine nature and graphs. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and how to create a tally chart.
Resources Pencil/Ruler/Paper Bags or Buckets Explanation How many leaves can you find within the woodland. Before you go out, make a prediction of what kind of leaves you will see, and record these predictions on a chart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spikey by Nature</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/spikey-by-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 22:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/spikey-by-nature/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Spikey by nature&amp;rsquo; is a joyful outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of spikey by nature is to collect many different types of leaves and count their spikes. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment, and how to create Carroll diagrams.
Resources Pencil/Ruler/Paper Explanation How many leaves can you find within the woodland. Use the Carroll diagram to record your findings. Use the diagram below to give you a head start (for lower abilities use other diagrams eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Under Here?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/whats-under-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 22:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/whats-under-here/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered what lives under logs and leaves? The aim of what&amp;rsquo;s under here is to combine nature and graphs. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and how to create a pictograph.
Resources Pencil/Ruler/Paper Explanation Your group could equally use tally charts, bar charts etc. Instead of using pencils and paper to record your pictograph, why not use an ‘Ash pencil’ and a piece of wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rehoming Creatures</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/rehoming-creatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/rehoming-creatures/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Rehoming creatures&amp;rsquo; is a focused group of activities that priorities on firstly finding out who needs helping and then focusing our efforts in building the homes. If you are looking for unique ways to engage yourself and other surrounding data collection then this section is where you should start.
These activities develop your; trust, cooperation, patience, teamwork, life skills, addition, estimating, and record taking. Each activity will ooze so many other benefits, so why not get choosing and try them out!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
