<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>featured on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/featured/</link>
    <description>Recent content in featured on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 22:40:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create a Nest Box on a Budget</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/pallet-wood-nest-boxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 22:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/pallet-wood-nest-boxes/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that with just a few materials, you can help birds thrive within your area by creating nesting boxes? This guide will help you look at how you can create a nest box at a low cost.
‌With the cold, dark days of winter becoming warmer and brighter, signs of spring are becoming more abundant. One of these signs are sounds of birds returning to our gardens and woodlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Spaces in Schools: Is the Government Doing Enough?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</guid>
      <description>Just a single encounter with the natural world can be a powerful and life-affirming event. Its innate beauty can inform our sense of purpose and significance, as well as capturing our respective imaginations.
With our growing appreciation for the natural world, it’s no wonder that the National Trust recently saw record numbers of visitors in excess of 26.6m  .
However, the outdoors aren’t just for adults. They can also play a profound role in the development and positive mental health of children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide To Creating An Effective Outdoor Learning Space</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/creating-an-effective-outdoor-learning-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 19:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/creating-an-effective-outdoor-learning-space/</guid>
      <description>The outdoors has proven to be an effective learning environment for children, but, for teachers and parents with little experience teaching in this environment, it may be confusing to get started. In this guide, we will address this issue and show you how to select and create the perfect outdoor learning space.
Words Matter According to recent reports  , the terms &amp;ldquo;Outdoor Learning  &amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Forest School&amp;rdquo; are becoming more popular, and those who have explored these avenues have learned how much this form of learning engages and motivates young children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosscaping: Ready for the Challenge?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mosscaping-ready-for-the-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mosscaping-ready-for-the-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Fancy the challenge of transforming an unwanted area outside, into a vibrant natural space for both yourself and living invertebrates to appreciate? If so then get your coat and boots on, get outside, get creative, most of all, have fun.
What is mosscaping? Mosscaping is where you use moss  to change the look of an area. It could act as natural cover for areas that at too damp and shady for other plant life to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Essential English Walks</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-essential-english-walks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 13:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-essential-english-walks/</guid>
      <description>Walking for pleasure has been a much beloved pastime since the birth of civilisation, and can have great health benefits. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking for some slow-pace, low-impact exercise, or an excuse to get out of the house and gather your thoughts, walking is readily available just about anywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s even good for digestion!
But what if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to step up your walking game and only the most picturesque walks will do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Topics to Consider Before Leading an Outdoor Activity</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/10-topics-to-consider-before-leading-an-outdoor-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 23:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/10-topics-to-consider-before-leading-an-outdoor-activity/</guid>
      <description>Do you feel that you could be missing out on essential information that can help you and your group have fun and safe experiences outside? This article mentions ten topics, which will help you to create a safe and solid outdoor activities.
Before leading an outdoor activity, there are a number of things to consider that will benefit individual experiences. Below are ten areas that will help you keep your group happy and safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Scenic Cycle Routes in England</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/scenic-cycle-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/scenic-cycle-routes/</guid>
      <description>Cycling can be a purely functional activity - allowing us to commute to and from work, visit friends or collect our groceries. Cycling for pleasure can provide us with an entirely different, much more fulfilling experience.
The physical effort that we put in to cycling is great for our bodily health; it offers aerobic exercise without the social awkwardness of a gym as well as the ability to strengthen our leg muscles, abdominals and glutes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
