<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Number on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/number/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Number on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:57:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/number/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How many steps?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/how-many-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/how-many-steps/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;How many steps?&amp;rsquo; gets people to come together to estimate distances. The aim of this activity is to count steps and use that figure to try and estimate a number of steps needed to reach a fixed point in the distance. This encourages children to predict distances.
Resources Paper/Pen Blindfolds Explanation Give the group a place to walk to. Before they start to walk to that designated place, they have to try and work out how many steps it will take.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number Swap</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/number-swap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/number-swap/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Number Swap&amp;rsquo; is a team oriented outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of number swap is to understand where numbers have to be and order them correctly. This allows children to listen to each other and work closely with others.
Resources Numbered Vests (optional) Numbered Log Discs (optional) Explanation Each member of the group is given a number (numbered vest/log disc). They all get into a line, and reorder themselves into the correct position depending on their number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treasure Hunt Counting</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/treasure-hunt-counting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/treasure-hunt-counting/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Treasure hunt counting&amp;rsquo; is a variation on scavenger hunt. The aim of treasure hunt counting is to match numbers with natural materials. This allows children to respect nature, the environment, and focus on materials not numbers.
Resources White marker paint pens Chalk Number logs (optional) Explanation When hunting for treasure within the natural environment, you will need to try and match your numbers. This means that if your number is for example five, you will have to think of a natural item that you can find five of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting Stick</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/counting-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/counting-stick/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Counting stick&amp;rsquo; will really help improve your number skills. The aim of this session is to use a stick to illustrate where certain numbers should be placed. This allows children to understand how to count up/down at any point.
Resources Scissors Paper/Pen String Explanation First find a stick, then tell the group that one end of the stick starts at zero and the other ends at ten (pick different ranges depending on their ability).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinnamon Sugar Doughnuts</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/cinnamon-sugar-doughnuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/cinnamon-sugar-doughnuts/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Cinnamon sugar doughnuts&amp;rsquo; are very tasty to eat, they are even satisfying to make too. The aim of cinnamon sugar doughnuts is to make doughnuts by following a recipe. This allows children to read the recipe and work out the value for each ingredient.
Resources Fire Kit/Water Buttermilk biscuit dough (refrigerated/cool) Vegetable oil 3/4 cup sugar 1/2 teaspoon cinnamon Plain Glaze (optional): 2 cups confectioners sugar 1/4 teaspoon salt 8 tablespoons unsalted butter (melted) 1/4 cup milk 1 teaspoon vanilla extract Explanation On a cutting board, separate the buttermilk biscuit dough and use the vegetable oil cap to cut a hole in the biscuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Style Buttermilk Biscuits</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/american-style-buttermilk-biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/american-style-buttermilk-biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Following a recipe can be tricky but creating something from numbers and instructions can be really satisfying. The aim of this activity is to make biscuits by following a recipe. This makes children read the recipe and work out the value for each ingredient.
Resources Fire kit/Gloves/Water (Bucket) Waxed Paper/Biscuit Cutter/Butter Brush 250g plain flour 4 teaspoons baking powder 1/4 teaspoon bicarbonate of soda 1/2 teaspoon salt 2 tablespoons cold butter 2 tablespoons vegetable fat 230ml chilled buttermilk (or natural yogurt (thinned) with whole milk) 50g butter, melted (optional) Explanation Combine all ingredients, then knead the dough by hand until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number Logs</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/number-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/number-logs/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Number logs&amp;rsquo; uses natural materials and crosses them with numbers. The aim of number logs is to use your sawing and counting skills. This allows children to better understand how to use tools safely and efficiently, and also gives them the opportunity to create numbers in a more tangible way.
Resources Logs/Hand Saw/Safety Gloves Paint/Chalk Board Paint (CBP) Chalk Explanation Collect logs from the nature environment, and use the saw to create thin discs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunt for Natural Colours</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hunt-for-natural-colours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hunt-for-natural-colours/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Hunt for natural colours&amp;rsquo; is a superb outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of hunt for natural colours is to use your hunting and counting skills. This allows children to better understand where to try and find items and gives them the opportunity to count for a purpose.
Resources Paint (different colours) Paint Brushes Paper Pencils Explanation Get natural objects (sticks, leaves, stones etc.) and paint them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Quantities</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-quantities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-quantities/</guid>
      <description>The woodland has loads of resources for you to create great quantities in either the soil, or on top of the soil. The aim of natural quantities is look into two activities; &amp;lsquo;show me&amp;rsquo; and fraction wall. This allows children to better understand quantities and also shows them how to represent a number in a different way.
Explanation Show Me Call out a number to your team and make them create that number by either drawing a tally chart, drawing a number (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavenger Hunt</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/scavenger-hunt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/scavenger-hunt-2/</guid>
      <description>Discovering a new place could be done by exploring for certain items. The aim of scavenger hunt is to use your hunting and counting skills. This allows children to better understand where to try and find items and gives them the opportunity to count for a purpose.
Resources Bags Explanation The scavenger hunt can be run by asking the group to pick up specific items e.g. find 3 different leaves or find 1 smooth barked tree.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
