<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Richard Fairman on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/authors/richard-fairman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Richard Fairman on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/authors/richard-fairman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Green Spaces in Schools: Is the Government Doing Enough?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</guid>
      <description>Just a single encounter with the natural world can be a powerful and life-affirming event. Its innate beauty can inform our sense of purpose and significance, as well as capturing our respective imaginations.
With our growing appreciation for the natural world, it’s no wonder that the National Trust recently saw record numbers of visitors in excess of 26.6m .
However, the outdoors aren’t just for adults. They can also play a profound role in the development and positive mental health of children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Shelters: The Top Five Techniques</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-shelters-top-five-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-shelters-top-five-techniques/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten your tent, and civilisation is hours away. Perhaps you console yourself with the romantic proposition of a beautiful night staring straight up at the unspoiled, starry sky. But no sooner have you lit a fire and picked up a good book do you realise that there&amp;rsquo;s a rain storm fast approaching!
Yes - it&amp;rsquo;s time to find out if mother nature can truly provide, and whether or not you have the resourcefulness to fashion the natural building blocks of the woodland into something robust enough to shield you from misery and failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Essential English Walks</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-essential-english-walks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 13:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-essential-english-walks/</guid>
      <description>Walking for pleasure has been a much beloved pastime since the birth of civilisation, and can have great health benefits. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking for some slow-pace, low-impact exercise, or an excuse to get out of the house and gather your thoughts, walking is readily available just about anywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s even good for digestion!
But what if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to step up your walking game and only the most picturesque walks will do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Scenic Cycle Routes in England</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/scenic-cycle-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/scenic-cycle-routes/</guid>
      <description>Cycling can be a purely functional activity - allowing us to commute to and from work, visit friends or collect our groceries. Cycling for pleasure can provide us with an entirely different, much more fulfilling experience.
The physical effort that we put in to cycling is great for our bodily health; it offers aerobic exercise without the social awkwardness of a gym as well as the ability to strengthen our leg muscles, abdominals and glutes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
