<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured Bottom on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/featured-bottom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured Bottom on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 17:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/featured-bottom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Learning Explained</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</guid>
      <description>For many years people have enjoyed embracing the natural environment. Playing in fields until tea time was the norm. Nowadays, our society doesn&amp;rsquo;t engage with nature as it used too. There have been companies, through the years, delivering outdoor experiences, but is this enough?
In this article, we will look at how new evidence and practises have altered society&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the importance of the outdoors. How the term outdoor learning, has been coined, and why our society should be embracing the outdoors on a wide scale, within their daily lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Outside and Play</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/get-outside-and-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 23:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/get-outside-and-play/</guid>
      <description>Play is a natural behaviour, instinctively creating imaginative stories, games, and activities, which help develop social, emotional, intellectual, and physical skills. This creative language can help children integrate themselves with each other and understand the world around them.
In this article &amp;lsquo;get outside and play&amp;rsquo; is defined as a way to naturally learn and develop their soft skills by experiencing nature in its true form. This is important because not all children are accessing outdoor play and not all children learn best in the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
