<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shape and Space on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/shape-and-space/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shape and Space on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:40:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/shape-and-space/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Natural Javelin</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-javelin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-javelin/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Natural javelin&amp;rsquo; is a creative outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of natural javelin is to combine your creative skills and the natural environment. This allows children to better understand nature, the environment, and how to use tools properly.
Resources  Different Sized ‘Woodland Based’ Javelins Knife, Scissors, Feathers, Thick/Thin Cord, Superglue, Marker Pen Tape Measure/Distance Measuring Wheel  Explanation Find natural javelins within the woodland and create a throwing area, by creating a throwing line with markers every 5/10 metres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are we nearly there yet?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/are-we-nearly-there-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/are-we-nearly-there-yet/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Are we nearly there yet?&amp;rsquo; looks at trust and the ability to estimate. The aim of this activity is to trust your partner and guess how long it will take to complete the course. This allows children to better understand how to predict a journey.
Resources  Stopwatch Ropes Blind Folds  Explanation Plan a route within the woodland that goes under, over and even around objects. Get the group to guess how long it will take to complete the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burn, Burn, Burn</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/burn-burn-burn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/burn-burn-burn/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered if that feather or leaf will burn? This activity will show you what burns, and for how long. The aim of burn, burn, burn is to try to estimate how long it takes different materials to burn. This allows children to better understand the structure of different types of materials.
Resources  Fire Kit/Gloves/Water Different items to burn (E.g. biscuit, grass, feather) Stopwatch Pencil/Ruler/Paper  Explanation Find different items that your group wish to burn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/tracking/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to follow a route that was made by one of your peers? The aim of tracking is to come up with natural signs that will help guide someone through your chosen path. This allows children to better understand how to create signs from natural materials and makes them aware of how many different signals there are.
Resources  Natural Materials Tape Measure/Distance Measuring Wheel  Explanation Get group to make a number of natural signs (left/right/forward/finish).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storyboard Shapes</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/storyboard-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 19:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/storyboard-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Telling a story using sticks and other natural materials might be fun, but making an the characters into shapes in mind blowing. The aim of storyboard shapes is to use your imagination and artistic flare. This allows children to better understand how to make shapes to tell a story.
Explanation Split the group into two or more teams. Each team thinks of a well-known story e.g. Jack and the Beanstalk, The Bear Hunt or The Stickman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Shapes</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hidden-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 18:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hidden-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Shapes are everywhere, all you need is to become more aware of you environment. The aim of hidden shapes is to first train your eyes to focus on shapes on a grid then to turn it to natural hidden shapes. This allows children to find shapes in a grid or within the natural environment.
Resources  Rope  Explanation Shape Grid Groups or pairs are to collect rope, Ivy or homemade cordage (made from nettles) and make patterns on the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Symmetry</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-symmetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 17:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/natural-symmetry/</guid>
      <description>Can you find symmetry within the natural world. The aim of this activity is to find natural material and use a mirror to investigate whether they have symmetry or not. This allows children to better understand how to look for symmetrical items in the natural environment.
Resources  Mirrors Scissors  Explanation In pairs, find leaves or other natural materials and place a mirror at 90 degrees at the mid point on the natural object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nangles</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/nangles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 16:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/nangles/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Nangles&amp;rsquo; enlightens people on how many angles they are within the natural world. The aim of nangles is to combine the use of natural materials with maths. This allows children to better understand angles and the natural environment.
Resources  Protractor String Sticks Scissors  Explanation Before setting out into the woodland or your local area, get two sticks and tie them together (sheer lashing  ). The sticks can be any size, but it is felt that the smaller the sticks are the easier it is to walk with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Kite</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-kite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 18:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-a-kite/</guid>
      <description>Kite making requires mathematical skills, resources, and determination to create a functioning kit. The aim of making a kite is to use your initiative and artistic flare. This allows children to better understand how to make a symmetrical kite out of a number of materials.
Resources  Plastic Bag (or paper) Sticky Tape Wooden Skewers x 2 String Ribbon Scissors  Explanation Diamond Kite  Create and cut out your diamond shape Size up two wooden skewers, (using the diamond shape as a template) tie together at mid-point to make a cross Pierce four holes on each corner and thread string through each of the holes, attaching wooden skewers to the diamond shape, making sure you leave excess on top for the ribbon (if you want) Tie a piece of string from the left corner to the right corner (horizontally), and attach another piece of string on the mid-point, make sure you have a lot as this is your ‘flying line’ To finish, attach ribbon to left, right and bottom corners  Other kites you might want to try making are known as;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blindfold Shapes</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/blindfold-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/blindfold-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Can you make shapes using a rope? This team related outdoor activity will push your communication teamwork skills. The aim of blindfold shapes is to focus only on the ability to listen to others and feel where the group want to go due to the connection of the team when creating a shape. This allows children to better understand each other and also have empathy with others who have lost their sight.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
