<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outdoor Learning on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/outdoor-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Outdoor Learning on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/outdoor-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Green Spaces in Schools: Is the Government Doing Enough?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</guid>
      <description>Just a single encounter with the natural world can be a powerful and life-affirming event. Its innate beauty can inform our sense of purpose and significance, as well as capturing our respective imaginations.
With our growing appreciation for the natural world, it’s no wonder that the National Trust recently saw record numbers of visitors in excess of 26.6m  .
However, the outdoors aren’t just for adults. They can also play a profound role in the development and positive mental health of children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide To Creating An Effective Outdoor Learning Space</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/creating-an-effective-outdoor-learning-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 19:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/creating-an-effective-outdoor-learning-space/</guid>
      <description>The outdoors has proven to be an effective learning environment for children, but, for teachers and parents with little experience teaching in this environment, it may be confusing to get started. In this guide, we will address this issue and show you how to select and create the perfect outdoor learning space.
Words Matter According to recent reports  , the terms &amp;ldquo;Outdoor Learning  &amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Forest School&amp;rdquo; are becoming more popular, and those who have explored these avenues have learned how much this form of learning engages and motivates young children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosscaping: Ready for the Challenge?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mosscaping-ready-for-the-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mosscaping-ready-for-the-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Fancy the challenge of transforming an unwanted area outside, into a vibrant natural space for both yourself and living invertebrates to appreciate? If so then get your coat and boots on, get outside, get creative, most of all, have fun.
What is mosscaping? Mosscaping is where you use moss  to change the look of an area. It could act as natural cover for areas that at too damp and shady for other plant life to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Outdoor Learning in Schools be Compulsory?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/should-outdoor-learning-in-schools-be-compulsory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/should-outdoor-learning-in-schools-be-compulsory/</guid>
      <description>If you had to choose between an education that offered your children an enjoyable learning experience that improved their social skills and made them generally happier and healthier, or one that didn&amp;rsquo;t, which would you choose?
If, that same educational experience were to improve the health and well-being of the teachers teaching your child, improve their job satisfaction and had a positive impact on their teaching practice, would you make that educational experience compulsory?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Learning Explained</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</guid>
      <description>For many years people have enjoyed embracing the natural environment. Playing in fields until tea time was the norm. Nowadays, our society doesn&amp;rsquo;t engage with nature as it used too. There have been companies, through the years, delivering outdoor experiences, but is this enough?
In this article, we will look at how new evidence and practises have altered society&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the importance of the outdoors. How the term outdoor learning, has been coined, and why our society should be embracing the outdoors on a wide scale, within their daily lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build an Inclusive PE Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-to-build-an-inclusive-pe-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-to-build-an-inclusive-pe-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>Moving from mainstream to special educational needs (SEN), the learning curve can feel like quite a jump. This article is aimed at teachers within primary education or secondary PE. It introduces SEN and talks about creating an inclusive PE curriculum, which is accessible for all learners. It explores taking skills from traditional games and explains how to teach them in natural environments, for a more inclusive PE lesson.
Types of SEN  SEN covers a vast spectrum of learning difficulties, which can include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of the Hidden Trident</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/in-search-of-the-hidden-trident/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 18:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/in-search-of-the-hidden-trident/</guid>
      <description>Your group are mermaids/mermens and they are trying to find the hidden trident. Only the trident will help them find the secret cave of Neptune. On your travels, you will see your friend Tallulah the turtle, who will help you in your quest to find the hidden trident.
The Walk Go for a walk around the area you wish to carry out the activities. Talk about mythical creatures and ask your group what they might think they would look like.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
