<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Themed on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/themed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Themed on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 20:37:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/themed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Insight into Sir Isaac Newton</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-insight-into-sir-isaac-newton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 20:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-insight-into-sir-isaac-newton/</guid>
      <description>Sir Isaac Newton was a genius and his discoveries are the foundation of a lot of scientific and maths theories. This theme focuses on one of his discoveries, which was &amp;lsquo;universal gravitation (gravity).
The Walk Go for a walk around the area you wish to carry out the activities. Talk about Sir Isaac Newton and ask your group, what they might know about him. If they don&amp;rsquo;t know then talk about gravity, laws of motion, and rainbows (refraction of light).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a Bug&#39;s Life</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/its-a-bugs-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 21:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/its-a-bugs-life/</guid>
      <description>What different types of creatures live in and around your area. You will focus on making a bug in both a physical form and picture. You will figure out what type of bugs live in your area, provide food for it and build a home for it too.
Your Favourite Bug   Do you have a favourite bug? What is it called? Create your bug using natural materials.
Bug Print   Make your masterpiece by using natural materials and paint, and then press the painted materials onto the paper to create your favourite bug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of the Hidden Trident</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/in-search-of-the-hidden-trident/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 18:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/in-search-of-the-hidden-trident/</guid>
      <description>Your group are mermaids/mermens and they are trying to find the hidden trident. Only the trident will help them find the secret cave of Neptune. On your travels, you will see your friend Tallulah the turtle, who will help you in your quest to find the hidden trident.
The Walk Go for a walk around the area you wish to carry out the activities. Talk about mythical creatures and ask your group what they might think they would look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tales of Robin Hood</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-tales-of-robin-hood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 21:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-tales-of-robin-hood/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the tales of Robin Hood, whereby, Robin has asked village folk if they have what it takes in becoming one of his Merries. This team are Robin Hood&amp;rsquo;s trusted steeds, who are all highly trained men and women.
The group of village folk have come to the edge of Sherwood Forest to be taken by Robin to a secret location deep in the forest, where they can train to become one of the legendary Merries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to The Fantastic Mr Fox</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-introduction-to-the-fantastic-mr-fox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-introduction-to-the-fantastic-mr-fox/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;An introduction to The Fantastic Mr Fox&amp;rsquo; is a section of themed activities that focuses on the famous story about a fox and his family, trying to outwit a bunch of farmers to survive. If you are looking for story based maths-focused activities then this section is where you should start.
The selection of activities are there to help develop; your trust, leadership, cooperation, patience, teamwork, life skills, and use and apply the maths knowledge within life tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction of The Elf Story</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-introduction-of-the-elf-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/an-introduction-of-the-elf-story/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;An introduction to the elf story&amp;rsquo; is a section of themed activities that focuses on a secret story about helping restore the elves city  , which has been destroyed by the dragon. If you are looking for story based maths-focused activities then this section is where you should start. The selection of activities are there to help develop your; trust, leadership, cooperation, patience, teamwork, life skills, and use and apply the maths knowledge within life tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
