<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contingency on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/contingency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contingency on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:08:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/contingency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Last Person Standing</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/last-person-standing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/last-person-standing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Last person standing&amp;rsquo; is a playful outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of last person standing is to not get tug. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment, and how to follow the rules of a game.
Resources  Stopwatch  Explanation A variation on tig but instead of one person being on, everyone is on. The idea is to survive till you are the only one playing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wave - Hide and Seek</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wave-hide-and-seek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wave-hide-and-seek/</guid>
      <description>This adaptation has revamped the classic game of hide and seek. The aim of wave - hide and seek is to find all the hiders. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment, and how to follow the rules of a game.
Resources  Rope (or use sticks)  Explanation The group creates a circle or assigns a designated area. A seeker is chosen and the rest go to hide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shoe Relay</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-shoe-relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-shoe-relay/</guid>
      <description>A great activity if you are needing to work on your shoe tying skills. The aim of the shoe relay is to combine speed and precision, to hopefully be the other team. This allows children to better understand team work, cooperation, strategy and express their shoe lace skills.
Resources  Shoes  Explanation The group is split into equal teams and lined up (sitting) behind the start line. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough for two team then just have one line and try and get them to bet their own time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giants, Dwarves &amp; Wizards</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/giants-dwarves-wizards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/giants-dwarves-wizards/</guid>
      <description>Have you heard of the classic game of &amp;lsquo;rock, paper, scissors&amp;rsquo;? &amp;lsquo;Giants, dwarves and wizards&amp;rsquo; is an activity that is virtually the same to play. Giants, dwarves and wizards to combine strategy and fare, to out wit the other team. This allows children to better understand team work, cooperation, strategy and express their creativity fare.
Explanation This is a slight twist on the ‘Rock, Paper, Scissors’. Go through the actions and make up a sound for each characters, which are;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helium Stick</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/helium-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/helium-stick/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Helium stick&amp;rsquo; is a challenging outdoor/indoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of helium stick is to work with others to pick up the stick, sounds easy, but not. This allows children to better understand team work, cooperation, and express their creativity.
Resources  A Long Stick Bangles or Washers  Explanation Group size: Ask the group to divide into two rows and stand opposite each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skyscraper</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/skyscraper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/skyscraper/</guid>
      <description>Can you make the tallest and strongest skyscraper? The aim of skyscraper is to work with others to create the biggest structure that can hold certain weights. This allows children to better understand team work, cooperation, and express their creativity.
Resources  Golf Ball Straws Paper Clips Scissors Tape Newspaper  Explanation Split group into teams, explaining about ‘Skyscrapers’ and that structures are getting bigger and heavier. The structure will be tall and hold a weight at the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Egg Challenge</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-egg-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/the-egg-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;The egg challenge&amp;rsquo; focuses on a team to create, discuss, and produce a vessel for an egg. The aim of the egg challenge is to create a pod that the egg goes in to help soften the impact once dropped at certain heights. This allows children to better understand their engineering skills, how to work best with others, and time pressure.
Resources  Eggs Natural Resources (Sticks, Grass, Leaves etc…) Scissors Tape String Newspaper  Explanation Split into teams and give them the challenge that they have to save ‘Humpty’ (the egg) from ‘THE GREAT FALL’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would you Rather?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/would-you-rather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/would-you-rather/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Would you rather?&amp;rsquo; is a great outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of would you rather is to decide which option you would prefer. This allows children to better understand themselves of what they truly would like.
Resources  A Rope Trivia Questions—Adapt questions to suit either the topic/ability/setting  Explanation Lay the rope out on the ground in a straight line. Ask the group to straddle the rope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spider &amp; Flies</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/spider-flies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/spider-flies/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Spider &amp;amp; Flies&amp;rsquo; is a version of the classic bulldog game. The aim of spider &amp;amp; flies is to combine speed and mobility to not get caught. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express their love for wide games.
Explanation This is a tame version of the classic bulldog game. One person is the spider and everyone else are known as flies, who stand at a base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth, Air or Water</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/earth-air-or-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/earth-air-or-water/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Earth, air or water&amp;rsquo; is a quick thinking outdoor/indoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of earth, air, water is to combine hand eye coordination and quick thinking. This allows children to work on their thinking skills and reactions.
Resources  A Ball or Pine cone  Explanation Ask everyone to stand in a circle. Throw a ball or a pine cone to a member of the group and say either ‘Earth’, ‘Air’ or ‘Water’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragons Breath</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/dragons-breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/dragons-breath/</guid>
      <description>This friendship bracelet activity can be used as part of a story where the wool is &amp;lsquo;dragons breath&amp;rsquo; and you need it to create a bracelet to keep you safe. The aim of dragons breath is to combine wool, teamwork and to create a unique bracelet. This allows children to better understand how to cooperate, work on their motor skills and express their imagination.
Resources  Wool (two different colours) Scissors Tape  Explanation Cut the wool and go to a tree or shrub and place all over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here, There, Where</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/here-there-where/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/here-there-where/</guid>
      <description>If you feel that your group just are not focuses, and you want to concentrate on their listening skills then this activity is great. The aim of here, there, where is to focus on concentrating to the three words. This allows children to focus on their listening skills, concentration skills, and better understand how to dismiss any distractions.
Resources  Three Big Circles (using rope or sticks) Open Space ( e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
