<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leader&#39;s Handbook on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leader&#39;s Handbook on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 21:09:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Code of conduct&amp;rsquo; is the foundation when performing activities within the natural environment. This page focuses on how to act within a natural space. It is important the group know at the start of their session how to act and respect the natural space.
Entering the woodland We will all be respectful of this great resource as we explore and play within it, but know that when we enter, we are entering the home of many different creatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equipment Guidance</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/equipment-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/equipment-guidance/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Equipment guidance&amp;rsquo; gives you an idea on what a leader may need when taking their group further afield. They will have to be aware of the group&amp;rsquo;s needs, different activities delivered, and know the environment in which these activities will take place. It can be a daunting task having to decide on particular equipment, which is why this page is here. Leader&amp;rsquo;s bag The leader is responsible for providing a safe environment for the group to work in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accident and Emergency Guidance</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/accident-and-emergency-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/accident-and-emergency-guidance/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Accident and emergency guidance&amp;rsquo; is essential to anyone whether indoors or out. The aim of this list is to help you have the confidence to know how to deal with a stressed situation, and also to make it clear on what information needs to be available for relevant parties. Whether you already have your own guidance, or whether you are new to this idea, it is important to be open to the information below as you might have missed a step.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
