<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Buckberry on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/authors/simon-buckberry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Simon Buckberry on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 16:33:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/authors/simon-buckberry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Has Our Culture Changed the way we Play?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/has-our-culture-changed-the-way-we-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 16:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/has-our-culture-changed-the-way-we-play/</guid>
      <description>30 years ago, many children would stay outside all day, playing and exploring, only to return when it was time for their dinner. The world we now live in is very different to the world back then. Studies have shown that since 2015, that one in nine children haven&amp;rsquo;t visited woodlands, parks, and beaches, and this is down to a number of factors. In this article we are going to investigate these factors and their impact towards play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There a Place for the Hidden Curriculum in Educational Settings?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/is-the-hidden-curriculum-starting-to-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 14:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/is-the-hidden-curriculum-starting-to-show/</guid>
      <description>Educational establishments, even though the focus is still on pupils passing their subject tests, teachers have become more aware of the importance of the hidden skills that children learn alongside these subjects. This article will look into why these hidden skills are very important.
With employers screaming out for soft skills such as grit, resilience, self-mastery and communication, clearly academic achievement is no longer enough. Despite the importance of the curriculum at all education settings, the teaching of softer skills are becoming more of a priority to young people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Outside and Play</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/get-outside-and-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 23:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/get-outside-and-play/</guid>
      <description>Play is a natural behaviour, instinctively creating imaginative stories, games, and activities, which help develop social, emotional, intellectual, and physical skills. This creative language can help children integrate themselves with each other and understand the world around them.
In this article &amp;lsquo;get outside and play&amp;rsquo; is defined as a way to naturally learn and develop their soft skills by experiencing nature in its true form. This is important because not all children are accessing outdoor play and not all children learn best in the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Hidden Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/unlocking-the-hidden-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 15:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/unlocking-the-hidden-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>The hidden curriculum considers what the pupil is learning as a side effect of the schooling process. The skill can be both positive or negative and is affected by social values, which a teacher holds and operates by. The article will look at whether the outdoors can help unlock the features of the hidden curriculum.
Michelle Sager (thought to be a pioneer in this field) has looked at understanding the hidden curriculum by connecting teachers to themselves, their students, and the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
