<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/about/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, children in the UK spend much, if not most, of their time indoors watching TV, using the internet or sitting in classrooms. Little time is spent interacting with the world around them. We believe that this lack of outdoor exploration may be impacting not only on their ability to learn and retain data, but also their mental health  .
New research  in this field has shown that outdoor learning  has made children happier, healthier, and more motivated to learn, and therefore it is important for schools to integrate this form of teaching within their curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/contribute/</guid>
      <description>A volunteer-run (no-one gets paid) project known as outlearn has been created to help schools and families, in supporting the younger generation through their formative years.
We are always on the look-out for skilled writers (with experience) who share our beliefs. Please read our &amp;lsquo;About  &amp;rsquo; page. If you still want to write for us, drop us an email (email address in the footer) and include links to your previous works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This website (outlearn) is provided as a volunteer-run project for schools and families that wish to support the future generation in understanding and benefiting from being in the natural environment. We do not intend to sell or distribute anyone&amp;rsquo;s data as this does not align to our goals.
The below information sets out how outlearn uses and protects the data collected via our website.
When using this site, you are legally bound to the following privacy policy, so please read carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
