<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anita Asken on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/authors/anita-asken/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anita Asken on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 10:55:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/authors/anita-asken/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The UN&#39;s Global Scheme to Protect our Environment</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/the-uns-global-scheme-to-protect-our-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 10:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/the-uns-global-scheme-to-protect-our-environment/</guid>
      <description>Have you heard of the Eco-Schools award? This article talks about why it was created, the importance of it and how schools can get involved.
In 1992, as a result of the UN conferences on environment and development, people at the conference felt that the only way forward in protecting the plant was to engage the youth of today. Since 1994, Foundation for Environmental Education  (FEE) have run the Eco-Schools programme globally to carry out the UN&amp;rsquo;s wishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Award to Help Pupils with Special Educational Needs</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-award-to-help-pupils-with-special-educational-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 14:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-award-to-help-pupils-with-special-educational-needs/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find an award that can help challenge special educational needs (SEN) pupils or even help bridge the gap from primary to secondary school? This article explains what the award is, why you should value it, a breakdown of the award and how to get involved.
The Junior Award Scheme for Schools (JASS) is owned and distributed by Friends of The Award  in Edinburgh and the Lothians (FOTA). This scheme is a holistic accredited learning programme for children and young people aged 5 – 14 years, which also works really well in an additional needs setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with The Duke of Edinburgh&#39;s Award</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/getting-started-with-the-duke-of-edinburghs-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 17:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/getting-started-with-the-duke-of-edinburghs-award/</guid>
      <description>In 1956, Prince Philip, The Duke of Edinburgh, created an award to help children and young adults gain vital life skills that are essential within today&amp;rsquo;s modern society. This article will explain how Prince Philip came up with the idea, and why it is essential for young people up to 25 years old. Also, it will explain the breakdown of the award, and how to get involved as a participants or leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Environmental Award that Benefits Young People and Families</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-environmental-award-that-benefits-young-people-and-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-environmental-award-that-benefits-young-people-and-families/</guid>
      <description>Have you wanted to take your child/class out to explore the natural world, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know how? This article highlights an award that gives structure and support to discover the outdoors.
In 1997, the John Muir Trust (the leading wild land conservation charity in the UK) created an environmental award scheme to encourage people of all backgrounds to connect with, enjoy, and care for wild places.
Origins of the John Muir Award John Muir Trust takes its name and inspiration from John Muir (1838-1914), the pioneering, influential Scots-born American conservationist, who was passionate about the wild.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
