<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creative on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/creative/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creative on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:20:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/activities/creative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grass Dolls</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/grass-dolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/grass-dolls/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Grass dolls&amp;rsquo; is a tactile outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of grass dolls is to create one or many little dolls that work on your motor skills, knot skills, and imagination. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources  Wool/Thread Scissors  Explanation Hold a clump of long grass in your hand, binding them together roughly in the middle, this will be the doll’s body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Sculptures</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-sculptures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-sculptures/</guid>
      <description>To be able to go into a woodland and simple create a wild sculpture is a great way of expressing yourself. The aim of this activity is to combine natural materials to produce a unique piece of art. This allows children to better understand nature, the environment and how to express their creative side.
Explanation Wild Sculptures Look for loose natural materials such as leaves, sticks, grasses, pine cones etc. Find a patch of grass and make a character like the Gruffalo or make a collage of a bird, a dragon, a monster or whatever inspires you when you look at the natural materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hedgehog Home</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hedgehog-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/hedgehog-home/</guid>
      <description>Help the hedgehog! We need to be more aware at providing homes for hedgehogs. The aim of this thoughtful activity is building a hedgehog home, which shows individuals how they can make a difference and provide homes for the little creatures. This allows children to have a better understand of nature and how to express their love for animals.
Resources  Bricks Plastic Box/Lid Newspaper/Straw  Explanation Choose a quiet spot that won’t be disturbed, maybe near a fence or hedge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaf Prints</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/leaf-prints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/leaf-prints/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to use the leaves within the woodland to make great pieces of art? &amp;lsquo;Leaf prints&amp;rsquo; use leaves as a resource to make natural art allowing children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity.
Resources  Strong Paper/Card/Material/Fabric/Plate/Dish Paints/Inks Brushes/Rollers Water  Explanation Try to find interesting leaves, either dip in, brush or roller on paint then press down onto paper, card, fabric or material (wood).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Storyboards</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-storyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/wild-storyboards/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever made a storyboard? This activity helps use tell great stories in a unique way. The aim of wild storyboards is to combine natural materials to produce a story allowing others to guess what it is. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity and imagination.
Explanation Split into two or more groups, then each group thinks of a well known story e.g. Jack and the Beanstalk, The Bear Hunt, Stickman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic Carpets/Flying Creatures</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/magic-carpets-flying-creatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/magic-carpets-flying-creatures/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Magic carpets/flying creatures&amp;rsquo; are fun-loving outdoor activities that aim to combine your designing skills with your imagination. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity and imagination.
Explanation Woodland Magic Carpets In a woodland clearing (open space), use sticks to make a frame. Fill the frame with a pattern or picture made from coloured leaves, seeds, berries and sticks. You could also make smaller frames, so that each person can design their own section of the carpet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Woodland Monsters</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-woodland-monsters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-woodland-monsters/</guid>
      <description>Within the woodland young children of all abilities are making their own woodland monsters. The aim of making these woodland monsters is to combine your imagination, creativity, and use natural materials to produce weird and wonderful woodland creatures. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity and imagination.
Resources  Clay  Explanation Look for interesting shapes in tree trunks, branches, tree stumps or fallen logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New World</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/new-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/new-world/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;New world&amp;rsquo; is a playful outdoor activity suitable for young children of all abilities. The aim of new world is to help your toys by creating a place for them to play. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and to express creativity and imagination.
Resources  Toy Soldiers Farm Animals  Explanation Find a space close by and create a miniature world in which the toys are the only non-natural things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elf House</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/elf-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/elf-house/</guid>
      <description>Suitable for young children of all abilities, &amp;rsquo;elf house&amp;rsquo; is a delightful outdoor activity, which aim&amp;rsquo;s to make either a home for an elf or help to build a village for all elves. This allows children to better understand nature, their environment and express creativity and imagination.
Explanation Firstly find a good spot to start the build. This could be among tree roots, in hollow stumps, within a pile of stones, or in a dip in the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Stick Characters</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-stick-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 22:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/group-activities/make-stick-characters/</guid>
      <description>This hands on outdoor activity, aim&amp;rsquo;s to make stick characters by combining natural materials to produce unique characters from clay. These character could have a role within a story or small play. This allows children to better understand nature, the environment and to express their creativity and imagination.
Resources  Clay Masking Tape  Explanation Look for the most twisted, gnarled stick you can find. Could it become a little man, a scary troll or a magical sprite?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
