<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qualifications/Awards on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/qualifications/awards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qualifications/Awards on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/qualifications/awards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Five Outdoor Awards that Help Guide Schools to a Better Future</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-outdoor-awards-that-help-guide-schools-to-a-better-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-outdoor-awards-that-help-guide-schools-to-a-better-future/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find awards that will benefit your school? This article shows five different outdoor related awards that will help transform your school for the better. Each award, in this article, will give you a summary of what their award is all about. This will give you a good understanding of whether your school is presently ready to taken on that particular award or not.
Giving children the opportunity to experience these awards, can help not just them but their local community, which will in turn help lead to the awareness of preserving the natural environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Gardening Help our Schools?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/can-gardening-help-our-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 11:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/can-gardening-help-our-schools/</guid>
      <description>This article talks about why the Royal Horticultural Society (RHS) developed an award for schools, and expresses the importance it holds for every child in education. It also breaks up the award, so it can be seen what is involved and why it is a valuable award to have in schools.
In 2007, RHS launched their campaign for school gardening as a result of the government&amp;rsquo;s proposals to change and improve child care, which was known as the &amp;lsquo;Every Child Matters  &amp;rsquo; programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Woodland Trust is Helping our Schools</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-the-woodland-trust-is-helping-our-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 21:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-the-woodland-trust-is-helping-our-schools/</guid>
      <description>This article explains how the woodland trust&amp;rsquo;s award for schools can help teachers inspire and educate their pupils around creating and sustaining our plant. It also breaks down the award, to make it easier to understand what each part consists of.
The Woodland Trust has devised a great award that schools can adopt for free. It was created as a project in 2008 and has helped children learn about and be inspired by trees, woods and wildlife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UN&#39;s Global Scheme to Protect our Environment</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/the-uns-global-scheme-to-protect-our-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 10:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/the-uns-global-scheme-to-protect-our-environment/</guid>
      <description>Have you heard of the Eco-Schools award? This article talks about why it was created, the importance of it and how schools can get involved.
In 1992, as a result of the UN conferences on environment and development, people at the conference felt that the only way forward in protecting the plant was to engage the youth of today. Since 1994, Foundation for Environmental Education  (FEE) have run the Eco-Schools programme globally to carry out the UN&amp;rsquo;s wishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Award to Help Pupils with Special Educational Needs</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-award-to-help-pupils-with-special-educational-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 14:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-award-to-help-pupils-with-special-educational-needs/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find an award that can help challenge special educational needs (SEN) pupils or even help bridge the gap from primary to secondary school? This article explains what the award is, why you should value it, a breakdown of the award and how to get involved.
The Junior Award Scheme for Schools (JASS) is owned and distributed by Friends of The Award  in Edinburgh and the Lothians (FOTA). This scheme is a holistic accredited learning programme for children and young people aged 5 – 14 years, which also works really well in an additional needs setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with The Duke of Edinburgh&#39;s Award</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/getting-started-with-the-duke-of-edinburghs-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 17:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/getting-started-with-the-duke-of-edinburghs-award/</guid>
      <description>In 1956, Prince Philip, The Duke of Edinburgh, created an award to help children and young adults gain vital life skills that are essential within today&amp;rsquo;s modern society. This article will explain how Prince Philip came up with the idea, and why it is essential for young people up to 25 years old. Also, it will explain the breakdown of the award, and how to get involved as a participants or leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Awards that can Help Students Move Forward</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 14:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-awards/</guid>
      <description>The UK&amp;rsquo;s education system works around academic achievements. Not all students are academic, which is why having extra awards added to their records of achievement (curriculum vitae) will show future employers that they are capable, and therefore deserve to be considered. In this article, it will talk about three outdoor awards that students can achieve. Helping them to develop a multitude of life skills, which will prepare them for life&amp;rsquo;s challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mark to Guide Schools Towards a Better Future</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/a-mark-to-guide-schools-towards-a-better-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/a-mark-to-guide-schools-towards-a-better-future/</guid>
      <description>Are schools ready to move towards a more interesting and engaging curriculum? This article talks about how schools can gain a particular accreditation (at numerous levels) that helps transform how pupils learn, giving them a more valuable school experience.
In 2006, the government released the Learning Outside the Classroom (LOtC) Manifesto  , explaining their vision to provide children with approaches to experiential learning as the main focus. Since then the Council of Learning Outside the Classroom (CLOtC) developed and supported schools going for their LOtC Mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are School Playtime&#39;s as Good as They Could be?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/are-school-playtimes-as-good-as-they-could-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/are-school-playtimes-as-good-as-they-could-be/</guid>
      <description>Schools have an enormous responsibility in making sure children progress, yet loosely supervised, unstructured free play known as &amp;lsquo;playtime&amp;rsquo; is not unfortunately what is focused upon. This is not their fault, as the pressure for progressive stats on school children has become a priority. This article gives schools the opportunity to gain advise in changing the way we manage &amp;lsquo;playtime&amp;rsquo; for the better.
Outdoor Play and Learning (OPAL) was founded by Michael Follett (Director of OPAL), who&amp;rsquo;s primary programme has helped hundreds of schools and early learning centres create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Environmental Award that Benefits Young People and Families</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-environmental-award-that-benefits-young-people-and-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-environmental-award-that-benefits-young-people-and-families/</guid>
      <description>Have you wanted to take your child/class out to explore the natural world, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know how? This article highlights an award that gives structure and support to discover the outdoors.
In 1997, the John Muir Trust (the leading wild land conservation charity in the UK) created an environmental award scheme to encourage people of all backgrounds to connect with, enjoy, and care for wild places.
Origins of the John Muir Award John Muir Trust takes its name and inspiration from John Muir (1838-1914), the pioneering, influential Scots-born American conservationist, who was passionate about the wild.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
