<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Activity on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/categories/activity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Activity on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 22:40:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/categories/activity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create a Nest Box on a Budget</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/pallet-wood-nest-boxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 22:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/pallet-wood-nest-boxes/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that with just a few materials, you can help birds thrive within your area by creating nesting boxes? This guide will help you look at how you can create a nest box at a low cost.
‌With the cold, dark days of winter becoming warmer and brighter, signs of spring are becoming more abundant. One of these signs are sounds of birds returning to our gardens and woodlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Shelters: The Top Five Techniques</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-shelters-top-five-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-shelters-top-five-techniques/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten your tent, and civilisation is hours away. Perhaps you console yourself with the romantic proposition of a beautiful night staring straight up at the unspoiled, starry sky. But no sooner have you lit a fire and picked up a good book do you realise that there&amp;rsquo;s a rain storm fast approaching!
Yes - it&amp;rsquo;s time to find out if mother nature can truly provide, and whether or not you have the resourcefulness to fashion the natural building blocks of the woodland into something robust enough to shield you from misery and failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosscaping: Ready for the Challenge?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mosscaping-ready-for-the-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mosscaping-ready-for-the-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Fancy the challenge of transforming an unwanted area outside, into a vibrant natural space for both yourself and living invertebrates to appreciate? If so then get your coat and boots on, get outside, get creative, most of all, have fun.
What is mosscaping? Mosscaping is where you use moss  to change the look of an area. It could act as natural cover for areas that at too damp and shady for other plant life to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ultimate Beginners Guide to Paddlesports</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-paddlesports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 20:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-paddlesports/</guid>
      <description>Are you feeling that there is something missing from you&amp;rsquo;re life? Do you enjoy activities that take you out of your comfort zone? If challenging yourself is something that would interest you, then why not try paddlesports?
In the UK, ‘paddlesports’ is the collective term for all paddling disciplines. In each of these watersports the paddler sits or stands on a board or vessel.
Beginners start paddling on flat water (lake or swimming pool) to develop basic skills, this helps them learn better control of their boat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Essential English Walks</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-essential-english-walks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 13:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-essential-english-walks/</guid>
      <description>Walking for pleasure has been a much beloved pastime since the birth of civilisation, and can have great health benefits. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking for some slow-pace, low-impact exercise, or an excuse to get out of the house and gather your thoughts, walking is readily available just about anywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s even good for digestion!
But what if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to step up your walking game and only the most picturesque walks will do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Topics to Consider Before Leading an Outdoor Activity</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/10-topics-to-consider-before-leading-an-outdoor-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 23:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/10-topics-to-consider-before-leading-an-outdoor-activity/</guid>
      <description>Do you feel that you could be missing out on essential information that can help you and your group have fun and safe experiences outside? This article mentions ten topics, which will help you to create a safe and solid outdoor activities.
Before leading an outdoor activity, there are a number of things to consider that will benefit individual experiences. Below are ten areas that will help you keep your group happy and safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Scenic Cycle Routes in England</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/scenic-cycle-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/scenic-cycle-routes/</guid>
      <description>Cycling can be a purely functional activity - allowing us to commute to and from work, visit friends or collect our groceries. Cycling for pleasure can provide us with an entirely different, much more fulfilling experience.
The physical effort that we put in to cycling is great for our bodily health; it offers aerobic exercise without the social awkwardness of a gym as well as the ability to strengthen our leg muscles, abdominals and glutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moss Graffiti: Dare to Try?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mossgraffitidaretotry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/mossgraffitidaretotry/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to create art with natural materials? Moss art or moss graffiti is a safe, interactive and enjoyable activity for families, schools and groups. This guide will show you different ways of using moss to have fun and reconnect with nature.
What we cover in this guide:
 the origins of ‘moss graffiti’ the development of moss graffiti, as an art form different types of moss graffiti; and how easy it is to get into creating art with moss.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
