<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Schools on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/schools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Schools on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/schools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Green Spaces in Schools: Is the Government Doing Enough?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</guid>
      <description>Just a single encounter with the natural world can be a powerful and life-affirming event. Its innate beauty can inform our sense of purpose and significance, as well as capturing our respective imaginations.
With our growing appreciation for the natural world, it’s no wonder that the National Trust recently saw record numbers of visitors in excess of 26.6m .
However, the outdoors aren’t just for adults. They can also play a profound role in the development and positive mental health of children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide To Creating An Effective Outdoor Learning Space</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/creating-an-effective-outdoor-learning-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 19:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/creating-an-effective-outdoor-learning-space/</guid>
      <description>The outdoors has proven to be an effective learning environment for children, but, for teachers and parents with little experience teaching in this environment, it may be confusing to get started. In this guide, we will address this issue and show you how to select and create the perfect outdoor learning space.
Words Matter According to recent reports , the terms &amp;ldquo; Outdoor Learning &amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Forest School&amp;rdquo; are becoming more popular, and those who have explored these avenues have learned how much this form of learning engages and motivates young children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Has Our Culture Changed the way we Play?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/has-our-culture-changed-the-way-we-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 16:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/has-our-culture-changed-the-way-we-play/</guid>
      <description>30 years ago, many children would stay outside all day, playing and exploring, only to return when it was time for their dinner. The world we now live in is very different to the world back then. Studies have shown that since 2015, that one in nine children haven&amp;rsquo;t visited woodlands, parks, and beaches, and this is down to a number of factors. In this article we are going to investigate these factors and their impact towards play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Preventable Disorder is Destroying our Children&#39;s Future</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/this-preventable-disorder-is-destroying-our-childrens-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/this-preventable-disorder-is-destroying-our-childrens-future/</guid>
      <description>Are less children experiencing outdoor environments? This article talks about why children don&amp;rsquo;t play outside in today&amp;rsquo;s society and due to this could be labelled with having &amp;rsquo;nature deficit disorder&amp;rsquo; (NDD).
NDD was coined by Richard Louv (American author) in his book, &amp;lsquo;Last Child in the Woods&amp;rsquo; to highlight the problem he sees for young children today, and for their level of experience within natural environments, locally or not.
Louv recounts his experiences with the local environment (woods, parks, rivers fields and forests) when he was young, to which his son asked him, &amp;lsquo;why were things more fun when you were a child?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Outdoor Learning in Schools be Compulsory?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/should-outdoor-learning-in-schools-be-compulsory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/should-outdoor-learning-in-schools-be-compulsory/</guid>
      <description>If you had to choose between an education that offered your children an enjoyable learning experience that improved their social skills and made them generally happier and healthier, or one that didn&amp;rsquo;t, which would you choose?
If, that same educational experience were to improve the health and well-being of the teachers teaching your child, improve their job satisfaction and had a positive impact on their teaching practice, would you make that educational experience compulsory?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There a Place for the Hidden Curriculum in Educational Settings?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/is-the-hidden-curriculum-starting-to-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 14:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/is-the-hidden-curriculum-starting-to-show/</guid>
      <description>Educational establishments, even though the focus is still on pupils passing their subject tests, teachers have become more aware of the importance of the hidden skills that children learn alongside these subjects. This article will look into why these hidden skills are very important.
With employers screaming out for soft skills such as grit, resilience, self-mastery and communication, clearly academic achievement is no longer enough. Despite the importance of the curriculum at all education settings, the teaching of softer skills are becoming more of a priority to young people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Learning Explained</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-learning-explained/</guid>
      <description>For many years people have enjoyed embracing the natural environment. Playing in fields until tea time was the norm. Nowadays, our society doesn&amp;rsquo;t engage with nature as it used too. There have been companies, through the years, delivering outdoor experiences, but is this enough?
In this article, we will look at how new evidence and practises have altered society&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the importance of the outdoors. How the term outdoor learning, has been coined, and why our society should be embracing the outdoors on a wide scale, within their daily lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build an Inclusive PE Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-to-build-an-inclusive-pe-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-to-build-an-inclusive-pe-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>Moving from mainstream to special educational needs (SEN), the learning curve can feel like quite a jump. This article is aimed at teachers within primary education or secondary PE. It introduces SEN and talks about creating an inclusive PE curriculum, which is accessible for all learners. It explores taking skills from traditional games and explains how to teach them in natural environments, for a more inclusive PE lesson.
Types of SEN SEN covers a vast spectrum of learning difficulties, which can include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Outdoor Awards that Help Guide Schools to a Better Future</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-outdoor-awards-that-help-guide-schools-to-a-better-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/five-outdoor-awards-that-help-guide-schools-to-a-better-future/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find awards that will benefit your school? This article shows five different outdoor related awards that will help transform your school for the better. Each award, in this article, will give you a summary of what their award is all about. This will give you a good understanding of whether your school is presently ready to taken on that particular award or not.
Giving children the opportunity to experience these awards, can help not just them but their local community, which will in turn help lead to the awareness of preserving the natural environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Gardening Help our Schools?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/can-gardening-help-our-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 11:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/can-gardening-help-our-schools/</guid>
      <description>This article talks about why the Royal Horticultural Society (RHS) developed an award for schools, and expresses the importance it holds for every child in education. It also breaks up the award, so it can be seen what is involved and why it is a valuable award to have in schools.
In 2007, RHS launched their campaign for school gardening as a result of the government&amp;rsquo;s proposals to change and improve child care, which was known as the &amp;lsquo; Every Child Matters &amp;rsquo; programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Woodland Trust is Helping our Schools</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-the-woodland-trust-is-helping-our-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 21:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/how-the-woodland-trust-is-helping-our-schools/</guid>
      <description>This article explains how the woodland trust&amp;rsquo;s award for schools can help teachers inspire and educate their pupils around creating and sustaining our plant. It also breaks down the award, to make it easier to understand what each part consists of.
The Woodland Trust has devised a great award that schools can adopt for free. It was created as a project in 2008 and has helped children learn about and be inspired by trees, woods and wildlife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UN&#39;s Global Scheme to Protect our Environment</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/the-uns-global-scheme-to-protect-our-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 10:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/the-uns-global-scheme-to-protect-our-environment/</guid>
      <description>Have you heard of the Eco-Schools award? This article talks about why it was created, the importance of it and how schools can get involved.
In 1992, as a result of the UN conferences on environment and development, people at the conference felt that the only way forward in protecting the plant was to engage the youth of today. Since 1994, Foundation for Environmental Education (FEE) have run the Eco-Schools programme globally to carry out the UN&amp;rsquo;s wishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Award to Help Pupils with Special Educational Needs</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-award-to-help-pupils-with-special-educational-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 14:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-award-to-help-pupils-with-special-educational-needs/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find an award that can help challenge special educational needs (SEN) pupils or even help bridge the gap from primary to secondary school? This article explains what the award is, why you should value it, a breakdown of the award and how to get involved.
The Junior Award Scheme for Schools (JASS) is owned and distributed by Friends of The Award in Edinburgh and the Lothians (FOTA). This scheme is a holistic accredited learning programme for children and young people aged 5 – 14 years, which also works really well in an additional needs setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with The Duke of Edinburgh&#39;s Award</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/getting-started-with-the-duke-of-edinburghs-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 17:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/getting-started-with-the-duke-of-edinburghs-award/</guid>
      <description>In 1956, Prince Philip, The Duke of Edinburgh, created an award to help children and young adults gain vital life skills that are essential within today&amp;rsquo;s modern society. This article will explain how Prince Philip came up with the idea, and why it is essential for young people up to 25 years old. Also, it will explain the breakdown of the award, and how to get involved as a participants or leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Awards that can Help Students Move Forward</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 14:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/outdoor-awards/</guid>
      <description>The UK&amp;rsquo;s education system works around academic achievements. Not all students are academic, which is why having extra awards added to their records of achievement (curriculum vitae) will show future employers that they are capable, and therefore deserve to be considered. In this article, it will talk about three outdoor awards that students can achieve. Helping them to develop a multitude of life skills, which will prepare them for life&amp;rsquo;s challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Topics to Consider Before Leading an Outdoor Activity</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/10-topics-to-consider-before-leading-an-outdoor-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 23:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/10-topics-to-consider-before-leading-an-outdoor-activity/</guid>
      <description>Do you feel that you could be missing out on essential information that can help you and your group have fun and safe experiences outside? This article mentions ten topics, which will help you to create a safe and solid outdoor activities.
Before leading an outdoor activity, there are a number of things to consider that will benefit individual experiences. Below are ten areas that will help you keep your group happy and safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mark to Guide Schools Towards a Better Future</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/a-mark-to-guide-schools-towards-a-better-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/a-mark-to-guide-schools-towards-a-better-future/</guid>
      <description>Are schools ready to move towards a more interesting and engaging curriculum? This article talks about how schools can gain a particular accreditation (at numerous levels) that helps transform how pupils learn, giving them a more valuable school experience.
In 2006, the government released the Learning Outside the Classroom (LOtC) Manifesto , explaining their vision to provide children with approaches to experiential learning as the main focus. Since then the Council of Learning Outside the Classroom (CLOtC) developed and supported schools going for their LOtC Mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Outside and Play</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/get-outside-and-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 23:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/get-outside-and-play/</guid>
      <description>Play is a natural behaviour, instinctively creating imaginative stories, games, and activities, which help develop social, emotional, intellectual, and physical skills. This creative language can help children integrate themselves with each other and understand the world around them.
In this article &amp;lsquo;get outside and play&amp;rsquo; is defined as a way to naturally learn and develop their soft skills by experiencing nature in its true form. This is important because not all children are accessing outdoor play and not all children learn best in the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are School Playtime&#39;s as Good as They Could be?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/are-school-playtimes-as-good-as-they-could-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/are-school-playtimes-as-good-as-they-could-be/</guid>
      <description>Schools have an enormous responsibility in making sure children progress, yet loosely supervised, unstructured free play known as &amp;lsquo;playtime&amp;rsquo; is not unfortunately what is focused upon. This is not their fault, as the pressure for progressive stats on school children has become a priority. This article gives schools the opportunity to gain advise in changing the way we manage &amp;lsquo;playtime&amp;rsquo; for the better.
Outdoor Play and Learning (OPAL) was founded by Michael Follett (Director of OPAL), who&amp;rsquo;s primary programme has helped hundreds of schools and early learning centres create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Environmental Award that Benefits Young People and Families</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-environmental-award-that-benefits-young-people-and-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/an-environmental-award-that-benefits-young-people-and-families/</guid>
      <description>Have you wanted to take your child/class out to explore the natural world, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know how? This article highlights an award that gives structure and support to discover the outdoors.
In 1997, the John Muir Trust (the leading wild land conservation charity in the UK) created an environmental award scheme to encourage people of all backgrounds to connect with, enjoy, and care for wild places.
Origins of the John Muir Award John Muir Trust takes its name and inspiration from John Muir (1838-1914), the pioneering, influential Scots-born American conservationist, who was passionate about the wild.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Hidden Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/unlocking-the-hidden-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 15:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/unlocking-the-hidden-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>The hidden curriculum considers what the pupil is learning as a side effect of the schooling process. The skill can be both positive or negative and is affected by social values, which a teacher holds and operates by. The article will look at whether the outdoors can help unlock the features of the hidden curriculum.
Michelle Sager (thought to be a pioneer in this field) has looked at understanding the hidden curriculum by connecting teachers to themselves, their students, and the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residential Trips are Essential for Children&#39;s Development</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/residential-trips-are-essential-for-childrens-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 23:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/residential-trips-are-essential-for-childrens-development/</guid>
      <description>In this article it will explain about an initiative that has shown overwhelming statics, towards the positive impacts to why it is important for children to go away on school trips.
In 2009, Paul Hamlyn Foundation invited a number of primary, secondary and special schools across the UK to work with &amp;lsquo;Learning Away&amp;rsquo; to develop and pilot original residential learning programmes. A residential trip is understood by schools and education establishments as an overnight trip.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
