<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Session Guidance on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Session Guidance on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:19:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding on a Session</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/safeguarding-on-a-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/safeguarding-on-a-session/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Safeguarding on a session&amp;rsquo; is an essential part in helping to keep members of the group safe from themselves, their team, and others external to the group. Every adult has to understand and be aware of what issues young or older people can be faced with. This page focuses on the leader having a responsibility in relation to child protection and also knowing the aims and how to approach the situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equal Opportunities &amp; Inclusion within a Session</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/equal-opportunities-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/equal-opportunities-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Equal opportunities &amp;amp; inclusion within a session&amp;rsquo; is important to be aware of. Everyone can learn in different ways, and the leader should be mindful that the group can have a range of different abilities. This will ensure that every member of the group will have a quality experience.
It is also important within each session to allow every member the opportunity of achieving the highest standards, regardless of ethnicity, religion, age, disability, gender, or background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session Structure</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/session-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/session-structure/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Session Structure&amp;rsquo; is a good way in making sure you have covered all you need to, before, within, and after the activity. The aim of this list is to help keep you on task, so that you do not miss anything that will hinder the quality or safety of the session. Within these lists you might have to click on to the links to explore more of what you need to bear in mind when taking a group outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Session Standards</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/general-session-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 15:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/leaders-handbook/session-guidance/general-session-standards/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;General session standards&amp;rsquo; are not essential but are a good way in making sure you stick to good practise. These standards that leaders should adhere to have been set down by Adventurous Activities Licencing Authority (AALA)  , and will ensure that a good level of risk management is achieved.
Leader’s responsibilities Prior to the activity the leader is responsible for:  Booking the facility (area that will be used for the activity) Conducting a routine visual and physical check of the equipment to be used Ensuring first aid equipment is available throughout the session Updating an on site/generic risk assessment if needed Collecting the group (conducting the signing out procedure if taking group off site) Signing out medication of individual pupils (if necessary)  During the session the leader is responsible for:  Setting out the aims of the session Running the session with a suitable level of challenge Group management during the activity Personal development  On completion of the session the leader is responsible for:  Feedback/review to group (through talking, pictures, ‘thumbs up/thumbs down’) Checking equipment for damage/recording use/completing logs as required Reporting accidents/near misses Collecting and returning the equipment Leaving the site/facility in a clean and safe condition  Sessions are physically and mentally demanding as well as incredibly fulfilling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
