<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/categories/environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/categories/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Green Spaces in Schools: Is the Government Doing Enough?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/green-spaces-in-schools-is-the-government-doing-enough/</guid>
      <description>Just a single encounter with the natural world can be a powerful and life-affirming event. Its innate beauty can inform our sense of purpose and significance, as well as capturing our respective imaginations.
With our growing appreciation for the natural world, it’s no wonder that the National Trust recently saw record numbers of visitors in excess of 26.6m  .
However, the outdoors aren’t just for adults. They can also play a profound role in the development and positive mental health of children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UN&#39;s Global Scheme to Protect our Environment</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/the-uns-global-scheme-to-protect-our-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 10:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/the-uns-global-scheme-to-protect-our-environment/</guid>
      <description>Have you heard of the Eco-Schools award? This article talks about why it was created, the importance of it and how schools can get involved.
In 1992, as a result of the UN conferences on environment and development, people at the conference felt that the only way forward in protecting the plant was to engage the youth of today. Since 1994, Foundation for Environmental Education  (FEE) have run the Eco-Schools programme globally to carry out the UN&amp;rsquo;s wishes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
