<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hidden Curriculum on Outlearn</title>
    <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/hidden-curriculum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hidden Curriculum on Outlearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 14:44:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlearn.co.uk/tags/hidden-curriculum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is There a Place for the Hidden Curriculum in Educational Settings?</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/is-the-hidden-curriculum-starting-to-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 14:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/is-the-hidden-curriculum-starting-to-show/</guid>
      <description>Educational establishments, even though the focus is still on pupils passing their subject tests, teachers have become more aware of the importance of the hidden skills that children learn alongside these subjects. This article will look into why these hidden skills are very important.
With employers screaming out for soft skills such as grit, resilience, self-mastery and communication, clearly academic achievement is no longer enough. Despite the importance of the curriculum at all education settings, the teaching of softer skills are becoming more of a priority to young people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Hidden Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/unlocking-the-hidden-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 15:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlearn.co.uk/blog/unlocking-the-hidden-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>The hidden curriculum considers what the pupil is learning as a side effect of the schooling process. The skill can be both positive or negative and is affected by social values, which a teacher holds and operates by. The article will look at whether the outdoors can help unlock the features of the hidden curriculum.
Michelle Sager (thought to be a pioneer in this field) has looked at understanding the hidden curriculum by connecting teachers to themselves, their students, and the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
